<TABLE_DEFINITIONS Table="SAINC40" Name="Property income" Source="USDOC/BEA/RD"><LINE><Code>90</Code><Description>Dividends, interest, and rent (thousands of dollars)</Description><Definition>Consists of personal dividend income, personal interest income, and rental income of persons with capital consumption adjustment (CCAdj).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>91</Code><Description>Personal dividend income</Description><Definition>Consists of receipts, in cash or in other assets excluding the corporation's own stock, from corporations located in the United States or abroad, of persons who are U.S. residents. Personal dividend income includes the net income of S Corporations received by individuals as well as their receipt of dividends from C Corporations. It includes imputed dividend receipts from pension plans. It does not include interest from regulated investment companies reported as dividends on individual income tax returns.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>92</Code><Description>Personal interest income</Description><Definition>Consists of the interest received (monetary and imputed) by persons, including individuals and nonprofit institutions serving households, from all sources.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>93</Code><Description>Imputed interest receipts</Description><Definition>Consists of 1) imputed income payments to policy holders by property and casualty insurance companies and life insurance companies; 2) financial services furnished without payment; and 3) imputed interest receipts from pension plans (including imputed interest attributable to under- or over-funded defined benefit pension plans).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>94</Code><Description>Monetary interest receipts</Description><Definition>Interest income that is recorded on financial statements.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>95</Code><Description>Rental income of persons</Description><Definition>Rental income of persons with capital consumption adjustment is the net income of persons from the rental of real property (except for the net rental real estate income of partnerships primarily engaged in the real estate business), the imputed net rental income of owner-occupants of housing, and the royalties received by persons from patents, copyrights, and rights to natural resources. The rental income of noninsured pension funds is imputed to persons and counted as part of rental income of persons with capital consumption adjustment.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>96</Code><Description>Imputed rent</Description><Definition>Imputed rent is an imputation for the net rental income of owner-occupied housing. It is based on the assumption that owner-occupants are in the rental business and that they are renting the houses in which they live to themselves: As tenants, they pay rent to the landlords (that is, to themselves); as landlords, they collect rent from their tenants (that is, from themselves), they incur expenses, and they may have a profit or a loss from the rental business.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>97</Code><Description>Monetary rent</Description><Definition>Monetary rent consists of royalties from patents, copyrights, and rights to natural resources and of net rents received by individuals, quasi-individuals, and private pension plans. It is adjusted for capital consumption and includes adjustments for uninsured losses to fixed capital caused by disasters, such as hurricanes and floods. It excludes the rental income of persons primarily engaged in the real estate business (which is included in nonfarm proprietors' income).</Definition></LINE></TABLE_DEFINITIONS>
