<TABLE_DEFINITIONS Table="SAINC70" Name="Transactions of state and local government defined benefit pension plans" Source="USDOC/BEA/RD"><LINE><Code>1</Code><Description>Current receipts, accrual basis</Description><Definition>Current receipts of pension plans consist of output, contributions, and income receipts on assets.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2</Code><Description>Output</Description><Definition>Output is the market value of the final goods and services produced by the labor and capital in a regional economy in a particular period.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>3</Code><Description>Contributions</Description><Definition>Contributions are the payments to government social insurance funds, to private and government pension plans, and to private insurance funds in order for a designated beneficiary to be entitled to receive the benefits provided by the funds.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>4</Code><Description>Claims to benefits accrued through service to employers</Description><Definition>Claims to benefits accrued through service to employers (also known as normal cost) is the present value of the additional benefits that plan participants earn from employment during the accounting period. The employer portion is called employers' normal cost, and the employee portion is called actual household contributions.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>5</Code><Description>Actual employer contributions</Description><Definition>Actual employer contributions are contributions to pension plans made by employers on behalf of their employees. Actual household contributions to pension plans are contributions made by employees from their wages and salaries.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>6</Code><Description>Imputed employer contributions</Description><Definition>Imputed employer contributions is a balancing term that equates employers' normal cost with actual employer contributions less pension service charges.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>7</Code><Description>Actual household contributions</Description><Definition>Actual employer contributions are contributions to pension plans made by employers on behalf of their employees. Actual household contributions to pension plans are contributions made by employees from their wages and salaries.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>8</Code><Description>Less: Pension service charges</Description><Definition>Pension service charges are payments for the administrative expenses of the pension plans.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>9</Code><Description>Household pension contribution supplements</Description><Definition>Household pension contribution supplements are the imputed income payments on assets to persons from the pension plans; the payments are reinvested as household pension contribution supplements.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>10</Code><Description>Income receipts on assets (including plans' claims on employers)</Description><Definition>Income receipts on assets (including plans' claims on employers) are the interest and dividends received from the
ownership of assets (such as bonds and stocks) plus the imputed interest on plans' claims on employers.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>11</Code><Description>Interest</Description><Definition>Pension plan interest consists of monetary interest and imputed interest on plans' claims on employers.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>12</Code><Description>Monetary interest</Description><Definition>Monetary interest is a form of property income received by the owners of certain kinds of financial assets (such as deposits, debt securities, and loans) in return for their investment in those assets.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>13</Code><Description>Imputed interest on plans' claims on employers</Description><Definition>Imputed interest on plans' claims on employers is an estimate of the plans' foregone income because of a shortfall in their assets (in the case of underfunded pension plans). The foregone investment income usually must be made up by the employer. In the case of overfunded pension plans, the extra investment income earned by the plans reduces the required amount of employer contributions, so the imputed interest will be negative.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>14</Code><Description>Dividends</Description><Definition>A form of property income received by shareholders in return for their investment in the equity of a corporation.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>15</Code><Description>Current expenditures, accrual basis</Description><Definition>Current expenditures of pension plans consist of the administrative expenses associated with running the plans, imputed income payments on assets to persons, benefit payments and withdrawals, and the net change in benefit entitlements.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>16</Code><Description>Administrative expenses</Description><Definition>Administrative expenses are the costs of operating the pension plans.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>17</Code><Description>Imputed income payments on assets to persons</Description><Definition>The interest and dividend income of pension plans is passed through to households as imputed income payments on assets; households then reinvest the same amount of income in the pension plans in the form of household pension contribution supplements.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>18</Code><Description>Interest</Description><Definition>Pension plan interest consists of monetary interest and imputed interest on plans' claims on employers.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>19</Code><Description>Dividends</Description><Definition>A form of property income received by shareholders in return for their investment in the equity of a corporation.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>20</Code><Description>Benefit payments and withdrawals</Description><Definition>Benefit payments are the amounts paid by government social insurance funds, private and government pension plans, and private insurance funds to beneficiaries according to the provisions of the insurance or pension plan. Withdrawals are lump sum payments of accumulated employee contributions upon leaving the employer.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>21</Code><Description>Net change in benefit entitlements</Description><Definition>The net change in benefit entitlements excludes the implied funding of benefits from holding gains on assets and excludes the effects on change in the estimated value of benefit entitlements that come from differences between actual experience and previous actuarial assumptions, changes in actuarial assumptions, and changes in plan provisions.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>22</Code><Description>Cash flow</Description><Definition>The cash flow of pension plans is actual employer and household contributions plus monetary income receipts on assets less benefit payments and withdrawals less administrative expenses.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>23</Code><Description>Actual employer and household contributions</Description><Definition>Actual employer contributions are contributions to pension plans made by employers on behalf of their employees. Actual household contributions to pension plans are contributions made by employees from their wages and salaries.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>24</Code><Description>Monetary income receipts on assets</Description><Definition>Monetary income receipts on assets is monetary interest plus dividends.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>25</Code><Description>Less: Benefit payments and withdrawals</Description><Definition>Benefit payments are the amounts paid by government social insurance funds, private and government pension plans, and private insurance funds to beneficiaries according to the provisions of the insurance or pension plan. Withdrawals are lump sum payments of accumulated employee contributions upon leaving the employer.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>26</Code><Description>Less: Administrative expenses</Description><Definition>Administrative expenses are the costs of operating the pension plans.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>27</Code><Description>Employers' normal cost</Description><Definition>Claims to benefits accrued through service to employers (also known as normal cost) is the present value of the additional benefits that plan participants earn from employment during the accounting period. The employers' portion of the cost is called employers' normal cost, and the employee portion is called actual household contributions.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>28</Code><Description>Interest accrued on benefit entitlements</Description><Definition>The interest accrued on benefit entitlements is the increase in benefit entitlements coming from past service due to the unwinding of the discount rate because retirement is one year nearer.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>29</Code><Description>Benefit entitlements</Description><Definition>Benefit entitlements are the present value of accrued benefits.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>30</Code><Description>Pension plan assets</Description><Definition>Pension plan assets are the net assets held in trust for pension benefits.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>31</Code><Description>Plans' claims on employers</Description><Definition>Plans' claims on employers is the difference between benefit entitlements and assets held by plans.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>32</Code><Description>Funded ratio</Description><Definition>The funded ratio is pension plan assets divided by benefit entitlements times 100.</Definition></LINE></TABLE_DEFINITIONS>
