<TABLE_DEFINITIONS Table="SAINC35" Name="Personal current transfer receipts" Source="USDOC/BEA/RD"><LINE><Code>1000</Code><Description>Personal current transfer receipts (thousands of dollars)</Description><Definition>Receipts of persons from government and business for which no current services are performed. Current transfer receipts from government include Social Security benefits, medical benefits, veterans' benefits, and unemployment insurance benefits. Current transfer receipts from business include liability payments for personal injury and corporate gifts to nonprofit institutions.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2000</Code><Description>Current transfer receipts of individuals from governments</Description><Definition>Current transfer receipts of individuals from governments consist of: Retirement and disability insurance benefits, medical benefits, income maintenance benefits, unemployment insurance compensation, veterans' benefits, education and training assistance, and other transfer receipts of individuals from governments.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2100</Code><Description>Retirement and disability insurance benefits</Description><Definition>Retirement and Disability Insurance Benefits consist of old-age, survivors, and disability (OASDI) benefits; railroad retirement and disability benefits; Federal and state workers' compensation; temporary disability benefits; black lung benefits; and Pension Benefit Guaranty benefits.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2110</Code><Description>Social Security benefits</Description><Definition>These benefits (old-age, survivors, and disability insurance benefits) consist mainly of monthly benefits received by retired and disabled workers, dependents, and survivors and lump-sum payments received by survivors.  The state estimates are based on annual tabulations of payments from the Social Security Administration (SSA). The county estimates are based on SSA tabulations of the amount of monthly benefits paid to those in current-payment status on December 31 by county of residence of the beneficiaries.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2120</Code><Description>Excluding Social Security benefits</Description><Definition>These are Retirement and disability insurance benefits excluding Social Security benefits.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2121</Code><Description>Railroad retirement and disability benefits</Description><Definition>These benefits are received by retired and disabled railroad employees and their survivors under the federal program of retirement insurance for railroad employees, who are not covered by Social Security. The state estimates of the benefits are based on fiscal year data from the Office of Management and Budget's (OMB) USASpending. The county estimates are based on payments data from the Census Bureau's quarterly Federal Assistance Award Data System (FAADS).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2122</Code><Description>Workers' compensation</Description><Definition>This compensation is received by individuals with employment-related injuries and illnesses and by the survivors of individuals who died of employment-related causes. The compensation is from both federal and state government administered funds. The state estimates of compensation received from the federal fund, which covers only federal civilian employees, are based on fiscal year data from OMB's USASpending. Compensation received by both public and private employees from state-administered workers' compensation funds consists of compensation received under exclusively state-administered workers' compensation insurance programs, compensation received under state-administered insurance programs that compete with private insurance programs, and compensation received under the state-administered programs for second-injury funds.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2123</Code><Description>Other government retirement and disability insurance benefits</Description><Definition>Other Government Retirement and Disability Insurance benefits consist largely of temporary disability payments, Pension Benefit Guaranty payments, and black lung payments.Temporary disability benefits are received by workers who are unemployed because of non-occupational illnesses or injuries. These benefits are from state-administered programs only in California, New Jersey, New York, and Rhode Island. The state estimates are allocated to counties in proportion to civilian population.Black lung benefits are received by coal miners who are totally disabled by black lung disease (pneumoconiosis) and by the eligible survivors of miners whose deaths were caused by the disease. Individuals whose eligibility was established before July 1973 receive their benefits from the Social Security Administration (SSA); those whose eligibility was established since June 1973 receive benefits from the Department of Labor (DOL). County estimates of the benefits received from each agency are based on data from the CFFR.Pension Benefit Guaranty benefits are paid by the revolving fund of the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC) to individuals whose PBGC-insured pensions cannot be paid by the private pension funds that are liable for the benefits. The national estimates are allocated to states based on payments data from PBGC. The state estimates are allocated to counties in proportion to Social Security benefits, which are assumed to reflect the geographic distribution of the retired population.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2200</Code><Description>Medical benefits</Description><Definition>Medical benefits include:Medicare benefits-- These benefits are Federal Government payments made through intermediaries to beneficiaries for the care provided to individuals under the Medicare program. Public assistance medical care-- These medical benefits are received by low-income individuals. These payments consist mainly of the payments made through intermediaries to the vendors for care provided to individuals under the federally assisted, state-administered Medicaid program and Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP) and under the general assistance medical programs of state and local governments. Military medical insurance benefits-- These benefits are vendor payments made under the TriCare Management Program, formerly called the Civilian Health and Medical Plan of the Uniformed Services program, for the medical care of dependents of active duty military personnel and of retired military personnel and their dependents at nonmilitary medical facilities.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2210</Code><Description>Medicare benefits</Description><Definition>These benefits are federal government payments made through intermediaries to beneficiaries for the care provided to individuals under the provisions of the Medicare program.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2220</Code><Description>Public assistance medical care benefits</Description><Definition>Public assistance medical care benefits consists of Medicaid, beginning in 1966, and other medical vendor payments.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2221</Code><Description>Medicaid</Description><Definition>Medicaid consists of Medicaid and the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP) expansion under title XIX of the Social Security Act.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2222</Code><Description>Other medical care benefits</Description><Definition>These medical benefits are received by low-income individuals. The benefits consist mainly of the payments made directly or through intermediaries to vendors for care provided to individuals under the federally assisted, state-administered Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP), and under the general assistance medical programs of state and local governments</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2230</Code><Description>Military medical insurance benefits</Description><Definition>Military medical insurance benefits are vendor payments made under the TriCare Management Program, formerly called the Civilian Health and Medical Plan of the Uniformed Services program (CHAMPUS), for the medical care of dependents of active duty military personnel and of retired military personnel and their dependents at nonmilitary medical facilities.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2300</Code><Description>Income maintenance benefits</Description><Definition>Income maintenance benefits consists largely of Supplemental Security Income (SSI) benefits, Earned Income Tax Credit (EITC), Additional Child Tax Credit, Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) benefits, family assistance, and other income maintenance benefits, including general assistance.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2310</Code><Description>Supplemental Security Income (SSI) benefits</Description><Definition>These benefits are received by low-income persons who are aged, blind, or disabled from both the federal government and state governments. The state estimates are based on Social Security Administration (SSA) tabulations of annual disbursements for two categories of SSI benefits: Basic federal payments and supplemental state payments. Both of these estimates are based on data that are published in the "Annual Statistical Supplement" to the Social Security Bulletin. The county estimates of the combined categories are based on payments data from the SSA.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2320</Code><Description>Earned Income Tax Credit (EITC)</Description><Definition>These are federal income tax credits for low-income workers, mainly those who have minor children. Eligibility for the tax credits is determined by the size of adjusted gross income, or earned income, and by certain household characteristics.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2330</Code><Description>Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP)</Description><Definition>These benefits, under the Supplemental Nutritional Assistance Program (SNAP) (formerly called food stamps), are issued to qualifying low-income individuals in order to supplement their ability to purchase food. Eligibility is determined by each state's interpretation of federal regulations; the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) pays the cost of the benefits.  The state estimates are based on tabulations of the value of the distributed benefits from the Department of Agriculture. The state estimates are allocated to counties based on payments data from the various state departments of social services. When payment data are not available, data on the number of SNAP recipients from Census Bureau's Small Area Income and Poverty Estimates program are used to extrapolate or interpolate.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2340</Code><Description>Other income maintenance benefits</Description><Definition>Other income maintenance benefits consists largely of general assistance; expenditures for food under the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC); Other Needs Assistance; refugee assistance; foster home care and adoption assistance; the 2008 Economic Stimulus Act Rebates; family assistance; Child Tax Credits; ARRA funded tax credits; other tax credits; and energy assistance.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2341</Code><Description>Family assistance</Description><Definition>These benefits consist mainly of cash and work-based assistance received by low-income families under the Temporary Assistance to Needy Families (TANF) program. In 1997, this program superseded the state-administered Aid to Families with Dependent Children (AFDC) and emergency assistance programs that received federal matching funds. State estimates of TANF benefits beginning with 1997 are based on fiscal year direct data from the web site of the Administration for Children and Families (ACF) of the Department of Health and Human Services.  State estimates through 1996 are based on unpublished quarterly data from ACF. State estimates for AFDC and emergency assistance for 1997 are based on unpublished ACF data for the federal grants to the states for fiscal year 1997. These data were adjusted to reflect (1) the number of months during calendar year 1997 that the AFDC and emergency assistance programs were in operation in each state, and (2) the fund matching percentage that was required of each state.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2342</Code><Description>Excluding family assistance</Description><Definition>These are Income Maintenance Benefits excluding family assistance.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2400</Code><Description>Unemployment insurance compensation</Description><Definition>Unemployment insurance compensation is made up of the following:  State unemployment compensation are benefits consisting mainly of the payments received by individuals under state-administered unemployment insurance (UI) programs, but they include the special benefits authorized by federal legislation for periods of high unemployment. The provisions that govern the eligibility, timing, and amount of benefit payments vary among the states, but the provisions that govern the coverage and financing are uniform nationally.  Unemployment compensation of Federal civilian employees are benefits which are received by former federal civilian employees under a federal program administered by the state employment security agencies acting as agents for the U.S. Government.  Unemployment compensation of railroad employees are benefits which are received by railroad workers who are unemployed because of sickness or because work is unavailable in the railroad industry and in related industries, such as carrier affiliates. This UI program is administered by the Railroad Retirement Board (RRB) under a federal formula that is applicable throughout the Nation.  Unemployment compensation of veterans are benefits which are received by unemployed veterans who have recently separated from military service and who are not eligible for military retirement benefits.Trade adjustment assistance are benefits received by workers who are unemployed because of the adverse economic effects of international trade arrangements.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2410</Code><Description>State unemployment insurance compensation</Description><Definition>State Unemployment Insurance Compensation consists mainly of payments received by individuals under state-administered unemployment insurance (UI) programs, but includes the special benefits authorized by Federal legislation for periods of high unemployment. The provisions that govern the eligibility, timing, and amount of the benefits vary among the states, but the provisions that govern coverage and financing are uniform nationally.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2420</Code><Description>Excluding state unemployment insurance compensation</Description><Definition>These are unemployment insurance compensation excluding state unemployment insurance compensation.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2421</Code><Description>Unemployment compensation for Federal civilian employees (UCFE)</Description><Definition>Unemployment Compensation for Federal Employees (UCFE) are benefits for civilian federal employees. It is administered by state employment security agencies (ESA's) acting as agents for the U.S. Government. The state estimates are based on data from the Employment and Training Administration. In about half of the states, the state estimates are allocated to the counties by county data or by local-district-office data using the same allocation procedure as that used for state unemployment insurance compensation. For the remaining states, the county allocators are residence-adjusted estimates of federal civilian wages and salaries.See Unemployment insurance compensation.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2422</Code><Description>Unemployment compensation for railroad employees</Description><Definition>Unemployment Compensation for Railroad Employees are benefits received by railroad workers who are unemployed because of sickness or because work is unavailable. This UI program is administered by the Railroad Retirement Board (RRB) under a federal formula that is applicable throughout the Nation. See "Unemployment insurance compensation."</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2423</Code><Description>Unemployment compensation for veterans (UCX)</Description><Definition>Unemployment Compensation for Veterans (UCX) are benefits received by unemployed veterans who have recently separated from military service and who are not eligible for military retirement benefits. The compensation is paid under a Federal program that is administered by the state employment security agencies.See Unemployment insurance compensation.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2424</Code><Description>Other unemployment compensation</Description><Definition>Includes trade adjustment assistance, Redwood Park benefits, public service employment benefits, and transitional benefits.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2500</Code><Description>Veterans' benefits</Description><Definition>veterans' benefits include veterans' pension and disability benefits, veterans' readjustment benefits, veterans' life insurance benefits, and other assistance to veterans.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2510</Code><Description>Veterans' pension and disability benefits</Description><Definition>These benefits are received primarily by veterans with service-connected disabilities and by the survivors of military personnel who died of service-connected causes. In addition, these benefits are received by war veterans who are 65 years old or older, who have nonservice-connected disabilities, who are permanently and totally disabled, and who meet specified income requirements.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2520</Code><Description>Veterans' readjustment benefits</Description><Definition>These benefits are the allowances for tuition and other educational costs that are received by veterans and by the spouses and the children of disabled and deceased veterans and for automobiles and conveyances, and specially adapted housing for disabled veterans.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2530</Code><Description>Veterans' life insurance benefits</Description><Definition>These benefits are the claims received by beneficiaries of veterans' life insurance policies and the dividends received by policyholders from the five veterans' life insurance programs administered by the Department of Veterans Affairs (DVA).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2540</Code><Description>Other assistance to veterans</Description><Definition>Other assistance to veterans consists of assistance received by indigent veterans from state and local governments, bonuses received by veterans from state and local governments and Veterans Choice and VA Community Care benefits.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2600</Code><Description>Education and training assistance</Description><Definition>Education and training assistance consists of the following:  Federal fellowships- These benefits consist of the payments to outstanding science students who receive National Science Foundation (NSF) grants, the subsistence payments to the cadets at the six state maritime academies, and the payments for all other Federal fellowships.  Higher education student assistance- These benefits consist of the Federal payments, called Pell Grants, for an undergraduate education for students with low incomes.  Job Corps payments- these benefits are primarily the allowances for living expenses received by economically disadvantaged individuals who are between the ages of 16 and 21 and who are enrolled in the designated vocational and educational training programs. These benefits also include the adjustment allowances received by trainees upon the successful completion of their training.  Interest payments on guaranteed student loans- these payments are made by the Department of Education to commercial lending institutions on behalf of the individuals who receive low-interest, deferred-payment loans from these institutions in order to pay the expenses of higher education.State educational assistance-These benefits consist of educational assistance provided by states to individuals for tuition and other educational expenses not including loans. The national and state estimates are based on data for state government expenditures for "other education assistance and subsidies" from the Census Bureau's annual State Government Finances.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2700</Code><Description>Other transfer receipts of individuals from governments</Description><Definition>Other transfer receipts of individuals from governments consists largely of other refundable tax credits; Bureau of Indian Affairs payments; Alaska Permanent Fund dividend payments; compensation of survivors of public safety officers; compensation of victims of crime; disaster relief payments; supplemental payments to UMW health benefits; compensation for Japanese internment; the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 funded Federal Additional Compensation for unemployment, COBRA premium reduction; Economic Recovery lump sum payment; ACA cost sharing reduction; Lost Wages Assistance; and other special payments to individuals.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>3000</Code><Description>Current transfer receipts of nonprofit institutions</Description><Definition>These payments consist of the payments made by the Federal Government, state governments, local governments, and businesses to nonprofit organizations that serve individuals. These payments exclude Federal Government payments for work under research and development contracts.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>3100</Code><Description>Receipts from the Federal government</Description><Definition>These payments consist mainly of the payments to private nonprofit hospitals for hospital construction and the payments to private educational institutions on behalf of the recipients of Federal fellowships, Pell grants, and other education and training programs.The national estimates of receipts from the federal government are allocated to states and counties in proportion to household population.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>3200</Code><Description>Receipts from state and local governments</Description><Definition>Receipts From State and Local Governments consist of state and local government payments to nonprofit institutions for education assistance and for employment and training.They are largely Workforce Investment Act benefits received by private nonprofit institutions that provide job training under a work-study program funded by the federal government (formerly authorized by the Job Training Partnership Act). The national estimate is based on data from the Monthly Treasury Statement. Because state-level data are unavailable, the national estimate is allocated to the states in proportion to household population.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>3300</Code><Description>Receipts from businesses</Description><Definition>Receipts from businesses consists mainly of corporate gifts of money, securities, and real property to nonprofit institutions that serve individuals.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>4000</Code><Description>Current transfer receipts of individuals from businesses</Description><Definition>Current transfer receipts of individuals from businesses consist mostly of personal injury liability payments to individuals other than employees.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>5000</Code><Description>Refundable tax credits</Description><Definition>Income tax credits are considered "refundable" if the amount of the credit that exceeds a taxpayer's tax liabilities is paid to them as a refund. Estimates of refundable tax credits include the amounts by which federal refundable tax credits reduce personal current tax liabilities and liabilities to pay contributions for government social insurance as well as the outlays that are distributed when the amount of federal refundable tax credits exceeds an individual's federal tax liabilities.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>5100</Code><Description>Earned Income Tax Credit (EITC)</Description><Definition>These are federal income tax credits for low-income workers, mainly those who have minor children. Eligibility for the tax credits is determined by the size of adjusted gross income, or earned income, and by certain household characteristics.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>5200</Code><Description>Additional Child Tax Credit</Description><Definition>This is a federal individual income tax credit for certain people with dependent children under the age of 17. People who qualify for the non-refundable child tax credit, and for whom that credit exceeds their total tax liability, may qualify to receive a portion of the excess as a refund. The amount refunded is the additional child tax credit.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>5300</Code><Description>Other refundable tax credits</Description><Definition>Other refundable tax credits consist of American Opportunity Tax Credit, Economic Stimulus Act Rebate, Making Work Pay Tax Credit, Government Retiree Tax Credit, Adoption Tax Credit, Health Coverage Tax Credit, Health Insurance Premium Assistance Tax Credit, Alternative Minimum Tax Credit, and Economic Impact Payments.</Definition></LINE></TABLE_DEFINITIONS>
