<TABLE_DEFINITIONS Table="SAINC45" Name="Farm income and expenses" Source="USDOC/BEA/RD"><LINE><Code>10</Code><Description>Cash receipts from marketings (thousands of dollars)</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from marketings consist of the gross revenue received by farmers from the sale of crops, livestock, and livestock products and of the value of defaulted loans made by Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC) and secured by crops.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>20</Code><Description>Cash receipts: Livestock and products</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from livestock and products is the value of gross revenues received from the marketings of livestock and livestock products during a given calendar year. This includes the marketing of meat animals such as cattle and calves, hogs and pigs, sheep and lambs; poultry and poultry products (including eggs); and dairy products. Also included is the marketing of horses, bees, animal aquaculture, and other miscellaneous animal species raised on agricultural operations.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>30</Code><Description>Meat animals and other livestock</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from meat animals and other livestock is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of meat animals and other livestock during a given calendar year. This includes the marketing of cattle and calves, hogs and pigs, and sheep and lambs. Also included is the marketing of horses, bees, animal aquaculture, and other miscellaneous animal species raised on agricultural operations.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>31</Code><Description>Cattle and calves</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from cattle and calves is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of cattle and calves during a given calendar year.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>32</Code><Description>Hogs and pigs</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from hogs and pigs is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of hogs and pigs during a given calendar year.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>33</Code><Description>Sheep and other livestock</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from sheep and other livestock is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of sheep, lambs, and other livestock during a given calendar year. This includes the marketing of horses, bees, animal aquaculture, and other miscellaneous animal species raised on agricultural operations.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>40</Code><Description>Dairy products</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from dairy products is the value of gross revenues received from the milking of dairy cattle during a given calendar year. This includes wholesale and retail sales of milk and milkfat from farm establishments. The processing and/or distribution of milk from a separate establishment not on a farm is classified in manufacturing, wholesale, or retail trade.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>50</Code><Description>Poultry and poultry products</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from poultry and poultry products is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of poultry and eggs during a given calendar year from a farm or hatchery establishment. Poultry includes egg laying chickens; broilers and other meat type chickens; turkeys; and other miscellaneous poultry such as ducks, geese, ostrich, pheasant, and quail.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>60</Code><Description>Cash receipts: Crops</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from crops is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of crop commodities during a given calendar year. Crop commodities include grains, such as corn, wheat, and soybeans; hay; vegetables; fruits and nuts; greenhouse and nursery products; tobacco; cotton; and other miscellaneous crops.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>70</Code><Description>Total grains</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from grains is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of grain crops during a given calendar year. Grain crops include corn, oats, sorghum, wheat, soybeans, and other grains such as buckwheat, rice, rye, barley, flaxseed, tung nuts, sunflower, safflower, sesame, miscellaneous oil crops, dry peas and beans, and popcorn.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>71</Code><Description>Corn</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from corn is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of corn and corn seeds (except sweet corn and popcorn) during a given calendar year.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>72</Code><Description>Oats</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from oats is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of oats during a given calendar year.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>73</Code><Description>Sorghum</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from sorghum is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of sorghum during a given calendar year.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>74</Code><Description>Wheat</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from wheat is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of wheat and wheat seeds during a given calendar year.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>75</Code><Description>Soybeans</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from soybeans is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of soybeans and soybean seeds during a given calendar year.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>76</Code><Description>Other grains</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from other grains is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of grain crops not elsewhere classified in a given calendar year. This includes grain crops such as buckwheat, rice, rye, barley, flaxseed, tung nuts, sunflower, safflower, sesame, miscellaneous oil crops, dry peas and beans, and popcorn.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>80</Code><Description>Hay, silage, etc.</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from hay, silage, etc., is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of hay, silage, alfalfa, clover, and mixed hay during a given calendar year. Mixed hay includes bentgrass, bluegrass-Kentucky, fescue, orchardgrass, ryegrass, and sorghum sudan.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>110</Code><Description>Fruits and nuts</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from fruits and nuts is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of fruits and nuts during a given calendar year. This includes citrus fruits, noncitrus fruits such as apples and grapes, berries, and tree nuts.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>112</Code><Description>Forest and maple products</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from forest and maple products is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of forest and maple products (except Christmas trees) during a given calendar year. After 1977, these receipts are classified in the estimates of "Other income" rather than in cash receipts from crops.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>113</Code><Description>Tobacco</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from tobacco is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of tobacco during a given calendar year.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>114</Code><Description>Cotton</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from cotton is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of cotton and cotton seed during a given calendar year.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>115</Code><Description>Other crops</Description><Definition>Cash receipts from other crops is the value of gross revenues received from the marketing of crops during a given calendar year of any kind grown under cover; nursery stock and flowers; mushrooms; vegetables (except dry beans and dry peas) grown in the open; crops not elsewhere classified including peanuts, sugar crops, hops, and mint.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>120</Code><Description>Other income</Description><Definition>Other income is comprised of Government Payments and Imputed and miscellaneous income received.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>130</Code><Description>Government payments</Description><Definition>Federal government payments to farm operators consist of deficiency payments under price support programs for specific commodities, disaster payments, conservation payments, and direct payments to farmers under federal appropriations legislation. The estimates of government payments are based on USDA national and state estimates of direct government payments.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>140</Code><Description>Imputed and miscellaneous income received</Description><Definition>Imputed and miscellaneous income received consists of imputed income, such as value of home consumption, and other farm related income components, such as machine hire and custom work income, rental income, and income from forest products (1978 to present).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>150</Code><Description>Production expenses</Description><Definition>Farm production expenses consist of purchases of feed, livestock and poultry, seed, fertilizer, agricultural chemicals and lime, and petroleum products; labor expenses; machinery rental and custom work; animal health costs; and all other expenses including depreciation. BEA adjusts the USDA state estimates of production expenses to account for methodological differences in the treatment of depreciation and to conform to BEA definitions and classifications.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>160</Code><Description>Feed purchased</Description><Definition>Feed purchased are expenditures for the purchase of feed by all farms during a given calendar year.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>170</Code><Description>Livestock purchased</Description><Definition>Livestock purchased are expenditures for the purchase of livestock by all farms during a given calendar year.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>180</Code><Description>Seed purchased</Description><Definition>Seed purchased are expenditures for the purchase of seed by all farms during a given calendar year.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>190</Code><Description>Fertilizer and lime (incl. ag. chemicals 1978-fwd.)</Description><Definition>Fertilizer and lime are expenditures on fertilizer and lime by all farms during a given calendar year. After 1977, this estimate includes expenditures on agricultural chemicals (pesticides), as well.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>200</Code><Description>Petroleum products purchased</Description><Definition>Petroleum products purchased are expenditures for the purchase of petroleum products by all farms during a given calendar year.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>210</Code><Description>Hired farm labor expenses</Description><Definition>Hired farm labor expenses are expenditures for hired labor by all farms during a given calendar year. It consists of hired workers' cash pay and perquisites, employers' contributions for social security and Medicare, and payments for contract labor, machine hire, and custom work.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>220</Code><Description>All other production expenses</Description><Definition>All other production expenses are expenditures not elsewhere classified incurred by all farms in the production of agricultural commodities during a given calendar year. It consists of repair and operation of machinery; depreciation, interest, rent, and taxes; and other miscellaneous expenses. For the years 1969-1977, this estimate includes expenditures on agricultural chemicals (pesticides), as well.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>240</Code><Description>Value of inventory change</Description><Definition>The value of inventory change is the estimated value of the net change in the farm inventories of livestock and crops that are held for sale during a given calendar year. This estimate is added to the estimate of realized net income so that the estimate of farm proprietors' income for a given year will include only the farm income from production during that year, or from "current" production.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>250</Code><Description>Value of inventory change: livestock</Description><Definition>The value of inventory change for livestock is the estimated value of the net change in the farm inventories of livestock commodities that are held for sale during a given calendar year. (See "value of inventory change.")</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>260</Code><Description>Value of inventory change: crops</Description><Definition>The value of inventory change for crops is the estimated value of the net change in the farm inventories of crop commodities that are held for sale during a given calendar year. (See "value of inventory change.")</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>265</Code><Description>Value of inventory change: materials and supplies</Description><Definition>The value of inventory change for materials and supplies is the value of the net change in the farm inventories of materials and supplies (i.e., purchased inputs such as feed, seed, fertilizer, and chemicals) during a given calendar year. (See "value of inventory change.")</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>270</Code><Description>Cash receipts and other income</Description><Definition>Total cash receipts and other income is a measure of the gross receipts of all farms. It consists of the following items: the cash receipts from farm marketing of crops and livestock; the receipts from other farm-related activities, including recreational services, sales of forest products, and custom-feeding services performed by farm operators; the payments to farmers under several Federal Government farm subsidy programs; the imputed value of home consumption, which is the value of the farm productions produced and consumed on farms; and the imputed gross rental value of farm dwellings.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>280</Code><Description>Less: Production expenses</Description><Definition>Farm production expenses consist of purchases of feed, livestock and poultry, seed, fertilizer, agricultural chemicals and lime, and petroleum products; labor expenses; machinery rental and custom work; animal health costs; and all other expenses including depreciation. BEA adjusts the USDA state estimates of production expenses to account for methodological differences in the treatment of depreciation and to conform to BEA definitions and classifications.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>290</Code><Description>Equals: Realized net income</Description><Definition>Realized net income consists of total cash receipts and other income less total production expenses.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>300</Code><Description>Plus: Value of inventory change</Description><Definition>The value of inventory change is the estimated value of the net change in the farm inventories of livestock and crops that are held for sale during a given calendar year. This estimate is added to the estimate of realized net income so that the estimate of farm proprietors' income for a given year will include only the farm income from production during that year, or from "current" production.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>310</Code><Description>Equals: Net income including corporate farms</Description><Definition>Total net income including corporate farms consists of the net income that is received by the sole proprietorships, partnerships, and corporations that operate farms.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>320</Code><Description>Less: Net income of corporate farms</Description><Definition>Net income of corporate farms refers to the net income of corporate farms arising from the current production of agricultural commodities. The estimates of farm cash receipts, other income, and production expenses include the income or loss from both privately owned and corporate farms. However, the income of corporate farms is not included in total net farm proprietors' income and is shown as a subtraction from total net farm income.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>330</Code><Description>Plus: Statistical adjustment</Description><Definition>The statistical adjustment to Farm Proprietors' Income is a simple mathematical rounding factor calculated to ensure that the sum of the state estimates, which are independently derived in thousand dollar units, add to even million dollar units at the U.S. level.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>340</Code><Description>Equals: Farm proprietors' income</Description><Definition>Farm proprietors' income consists of the income that is received by the sole proprietorships and the partnerships that operate farms. It excludes the income that is received by corporate farms.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>350</Code><Description>Plus: Farm wages and salaries</Description><Definition>Farm wages and salaries are comprised of the cash wages and pay-in-kind of hired laborers directly involved in the production of agricultural commodities, either livestock or crops. It includes the salaries received by the owner-operators of farm sole proprietorships, partnerships, and family held corporations.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>360</Code><Description>Plus: Farm supplements to wages and salaries</Description><Definition>Farm supplements to wages and salaries consists of the contributions of farm employers to privately administered workmen's compensation, pensions, and welfare plans; and of the contributions of farm employers for government social insurance.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>370</Code><Description>Equals: Farm earnings</Description><Definition>Farm labor and proprietors' income is comprised of the net income of sole proprietors, partners, and hired laborers arising directly from the current production of agricultural commodities, either livestock or crops. It includes net farm proprietors' income and the wages and salaries, pay-in-kind, and other labor income of hired farm laborers; but specifically excludes the income of farm corporations.</Definition></LINE></TABLE_DEFINITIONS>
