<TABLE_DEFINITIONS Table="SAINC91" Name="Gross flow of earnings" Source="USDOC/BEA/RD"><LINE><Code>10</Code><Description>Inflows of earnings</Description><Definition>BEA's estimates of gross commuters' flows reflect the annual earnings of in-commuters and out-commuters for a given area. The gross commuters' earnings flows are internally consistent with BEA's Regional Economic Accounts and may be used in conjunction with other BEA regional economic data for a variety of purposes, such as to assess the impact of local commuting on income growth for an area.BEA's estimates of gross commuters' earnings inflows and outflows are derived from the residence adjustment estimates, which are the estimates of the net inflows of the earnings of inter-area commuters. In the personal income accounts, the residence adjustment estimates are added to place-of-work earnings estimates to yield place-of-residence earnings estimates. This conversion process is an important part of the local area economic accounts because personal income is a place-of-residence measure, whereas the data used to estimate over 60 percent of personal income is reported on a place-of-work basis.Because in- and out-commuters' earnings are not directly observable from year to year but must be indirectly inferred through American Community Survey (ACS) data available from the Census Bureau, the residence adjustment estimation procedures use several data sources to produce intercensal estimates of gross commuters' earnings on an annual basis.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>20</Code><Description>Outflows of earnings</Description><Definition>BEA's estimates of gross commuters' flows reflect the annual earnings of in-commuters and out-commuters for a given area. The gross commuters' earnings flows are internally consistent with BEA's Regional Economic Accounts and may be used in conjunction with other BEA regional economic data for a variety of purposes, such as to assess the impact of local commuting on income growth for an area.BEA's estimates of gross commuters' earnings inflows and outflows are derived from the residence adjustment estimates, which are the estimates of the net inflows of the earnings of inter-area commuters. In the personal income accounts, the residence adjustment estimates are added to place-of-work earnings estimates to yield place-of-residence earnings estimates. This conversion process is an important part of the local area economic accounts because personal income is a place-of-residence measure, whereas the data used to estimate over 60 percent of personal income is reported on a place-of-work basis.Because in- and out-commuters' earnings are not directly observable from year to year but must be indirectly inferred through American Community Survey (ACS) data available from the Census Bureau, the residence adjustment estimation procedures use several data sources to produce intercensal estimates of gross commuters' earnings on an annual basis.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>30</Code><Description>Adjustment for residence</Description><Definition>An adjustment made to those components of earnings and employee contributions to social insurance programs (income subject to adjustment) that are reported on a place-of-work basis to convert them to a place-of-residence basis reflecting the net flow of income of interarea commuters. For example, the source data for wages and salaries represent the wages paid by the establishments located in an area. The wages and salaries that the establishments of a given area pay to workers who live outside that area are treated as an outflow and the wages and salaries that the residents of that area receive from establishments located outside that area are treated as an inflow. The adjustment for residence for an area, then, is the net of the inflows to that area and the outflows from that area.</Definition></LINE></TABLE_DEFINITIONS>
