<TABLE_DEFINITIONS Table="SAGDP8N" Name="Chain-type quantity indexes for real GDP by state (2017=100.0)" Source="USDOC/BEA/RD"><LINE><Code>1</Code><Description>All industry total</Description><Definition>The All industry total includes all Private industries and Government.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2</Code><Description>Private industries</Description><Definition>This sector includes all economic enterprises owned by individuals or groups, as opposed to public sector or government entities. Private industries include corporations, cooperatives, trusts, partnerships and sole proprietorships.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>3</Code><Description>Agriculture, forestry, fishing and hunting</Description><Definition>Industries in the Agriculture, forestry, fishing and hunting NAICS sector include establishments primarily engaged in growing crops, raising animals, harvesting timber, harvesting fish and other animals from a farm, ranch or their natural habitats. These establishments are often described as farms, ranches, dairies, greenhouses, nurseries, orchards or hatcheries. The sector includes two basic activities: crop and animal production (farms) and forestry, fishing, and related activities.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>4</Code><Description>Farms</Description><Definition>[NAICS] Farms includes crop and animal production. The crop production subsector grow crops mainly for food and fiber. These comprise establishments, such as farms, orchards, groves, greenhouses, and nurseries, primarily engaged in growing crops, plants, vines or trees and their seeds.Industries in the Animal Production subsector raise or fatten animals for the sale of animals or animal products. These compromise establishments, such as ranches, farms, and feedlots, primarily engaged in keeping, grazing, breeding or feeding animals. These animals are kept for the products they yield or for eventual sale. [SIC] Composed of SIC Major Group 01, "Agricultural Production-Crops", and Major Group 02, "Agricultural Production-Livestock and Animal Specialties."</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>5</Code><Description>Forestry, fishing, and related activities</Description><Definition>The Forestry, fishing, related activities NAICS sector comprises establishments primarily engaged in harvesting timber, and harvesting fish and other animals from a farm, ranch, or their natural habitats.The sector distinguishes one basic activity: agricultural support. Agricultural support activities include establishments that perform one or more activities associated with farm operation, such as soil preparation, planting, harvesting, and management, on a contract or fee basis.Excluded from the Forestry, Hunting and Fishing sector are establishments primarily engaged in agricultural research and establishments primarily engaged in administering programs for regulating and conserving land, mineral, wildlife, and forest use. These establishments are classified in Industry 54171, Research and Development in the Physical, Engineering, and Life Sciences; and Industry 92412, Administration of Conservation Programs, respectively.Industries in the Fishing, Hunting, and Trapping subsector harvest fish and other wild animals from their natural habitats and are dependent upon a continued supply of the natural resource. The harvesting of fish is the predominant economic activity of this subsector and it usually requires specialized vessels that, by the nature of their size, configuration and equipment, are not suitable for any other type of production, such as transportation.Hunting and trapping activities utilize a wide variety of production processes and are classified in the same subsector as fishing because the availability of resources and the constraints imposed, such as conservation requirements and proper habitat maintenance, are similar.Industries in the Forestry and Logging subsector grow and harvest timber on a long production cycle (i.e., of 10 years or more). Long production cycles use different production processes than short production cycles, which require more horticultural interventions prior to harvest, resulting in processes more similar to those found in the Crop Production subsector. Consequently, Christmas tree production and other production involving production cycles of less than 10 years, are classified in the Crop Production subsector.Industries in this subsector specialize in different stages of the production cycle. Reforestation requires production of seedlings in specialized nurseries. Timber production requires natural forest or suitable areas of land that are available for a long duration. The maturation time for timber depends upon the species of tree, the climatic conditions of the region, and the intended purpose of the timber. The harvesting of timber (except when done on an extremely small scale) requires specialized machinery unique to the industry. Establishments gathering forest products, such as gums, barks, balsam needles, rhizomes, fibers, Spanish moss, and ginseng and truffles, are also included in this subsector.Industries in the Support Activities for Agriculture and Forestry subsector provide support services that are an essential part of agricultural and forestry production. These support activities may be performed by the agriculture or forestry producing establishment or conducted independently as an alternative source of inputs required for the production process for a given crop, animal, or forestry industry. Establishments that primarily perform these activities independent of the agriculture or forestry producing establishment are in this subsector.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>6</Code><Description>Mining, quarrying, and oil and gas extraction</Description><Definition>This sector under NAICS comprises establishments that extract naturally occurring mineral solids, such as coal and ores; liquid minerals, such as crude petroleum; and gases, such as natural gas. The term mining is used in the broad sense to include quarrying, well operations, beneficiating (e.g., crushing, screening, washing, and flotation), and other preparation customarily performed at the mine site, or as a part of mining activity. The Mining sector distinguishes two basic activities: mine operation and mining support activities. Mine operation includes establishments operating mines, quarries, or oil and gas wells on their own account or for others on a contract or fee basis. Mining support activities include establishments that perform exploration (except geophysical surveying) and/or other mining services on a contract or fee basis (except mine site preparation and construction of oil/gas pipelines).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>7</Code><Description>Oil and gas extraction</Description><Definition>The category "Oil and gas extraction" is used in both the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems.SIC definition:This major SIC group includes establishments primarily engaged in: (1) producing crude petroleum and natural gas; (2) extracting oil from oil sands and oil shale; (3) producing natural gasoline and cycle condensate; and (4) producing gas and hydrocarbon liquids form coal at the mine site. Types of activities included are exploration, drilling, oil and gas well operation and maintenance, the operation of natural gasoline and cycle plants, and the gasification, liquefaction, and pyrolysis of coal at the mine site. This major group also includes such basic activities as emulsion breaking and desilting of crude petroleum in the preparation of oil and gas customarily done at the field site. NAICS definition:Industries in the Oil and Gas Extraction NAICS subsector operate and/or develop oil and gas field properties. Such activities may include exploration for crude petroleum and natural gas; drilling, completing, and equipping wells; operating separators, emulsion breakers, desilting equipment, and field gathering lines for crude petroleum and natural gas; and all other activities in the preparation of oil and gas up to the point of shipment from the producing property. This subsector includes the production of crude petroleum, the mining and extraction of oil from oil shale and oil sands, and the production of natural gas, sulfur recovery from natural gas, and recovery of hydrocarbon liquids.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>8</Code><Description>Mining (except oil and gas)</Description><Definition>Industries in the Mining (except Oil and Gas) NAICS subsector primarily engage in mining, mine site development, and beneficiating (i.e., preparing) metallic minerals and nonmetallic minerals, including coal. The term "mining" is used in the broad sense to include ore extraction, quarrying, and beneficiating (e.g., crushing, screening, washing, sizing, concentrating, and flotation), customarily done at the mine site.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>9</Code><Description>Support activities for mining</Description><Definition>Industries in the Support Activities for Mining NAICS subsector group establishments primarily providing support services, on a contract or fee basis, required for the mining and quarrying of minerals and for the extraction of oil and gas. Establishments performing exploration (except geophysical surveying and mapping) for minerals, on a contract or fee basis, are included in this subsector. Exploration includes traditional prospecting methods, such as taking core samples and making geological observations at prospective sites.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>10</Code><Description>Utilities</Description><Definition>The Utilities NAICS sector comprises establishments engaged in the provision of the following utility services: electric power, natural gas, steam supply, water supply, and sewage removal. Within this sector, the specific activities associated with the utility services provided vary by utility: electric power includes generation, transmission, and distribution; natural gas includes distribution; steam supply includes provision and/or distribution; water supply includes treatment and distribution; and sewage removal includes collection, treatment, and disposal of waste through sewer systems and sewage treatment facilities.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>11</Code><Description>Construction</Description><Definition>The term "construction" is used in both the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:This SIC division includes establishments primarily engaged in construction. The term construction includes new work, additions, alterations, reconstruction, installations, and repairs. Construction activities are generally administered or managed from a relatively fixed place of business, but the actual construction work is performed at one or more different sites. If a company has more than one relatively fixed place of business from which it undertakes or manages construction activities and for which separate data on the number of employees, payroll, receipts, and other establishment-type records are maintained, each such place of business is considered a separate construction establishment. Three broad types of construction activity are covered: (1) building construction by general contractors or by operative builders; (2) heavy construction other than building by general contractors and special trade contractors; and (3) construction activity by other special trade contractors. NAICS definition:The construction (NAICS) sector comprises establishments primarily engaged in the construction of buildings or engineering projects (e.g., highways an utility systems). Establishments primarily engaged in the preparation of sites for new construction and establishments primarily engaged in subdividing land for sale as building sites also are included in this sector. Construction work done may include new work, additions, alterations, or maintenance and repairs. Activities of these establishments generally are managed at a fixed place of business, but they usually perform construction activities at multiple project sites. Production responsibilities in this sector are usually specified in (1) contracts with the owners of construction projects (prime contracts) or (2) contracts with other construction establishments (subcontracts).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>12</Code><Description>Manufacturing</Description><Definition>The term "Manufacturing" is used in both the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:The manufacturing SIC division includes establishments engaged in the mechanical or chemical transformation of materials or substances into new products. These establishments are usually described as plants, factories, or mills and characteristically use power driven machines and materials handling equipment. Establishments engaged in assembling component parts of manufactured products are also considered manufacturing if the new product is neither a structure nor other fixed improvement. Also included is the blending of materials, such as lubricating oils, plastics resins, or liquors. NAICS definition:The Manufacturing NAICS sector comprises establishments engaged in the mechanical, physical, or chemical transformation of materials, substances, or components into new products. The assembling of component parts of manufactured products is considered manufacturing, except in cases where the activity is appropriately classified in Sector 23, Construction. Establishments in the Manufacturing sector are often described as plants, factories, or mills and characteristically use power-driven machines and materials-handling equipment. However, establishments that transform materials or substances into new products by hand or in the worker's home and those engaged in selling to the general public products made on the same premises from which they are sold, such as bakeries, candy stores, and custom tailors, may also be included in this sector. Manufacturing establishments may process materials or may contract with other establishments to process their materials for them. Both types of establishments are included in manufacturing.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>13</Code><Description>Durable goods manufacturing</Description><Definition>Consists primarily of tangible products that can be stored or inventoried and that can be used repeatedly or continuously over a prolonged period. This sub-group of manufacturing is not defined within the SIC or NAICS coding structure.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>14</Code><Description>Wood product manufacturing</Description><Definition>Industries in the Wood Product Manufacturing NAICS subsector manufacture wood products, such as lumber, plywood, veneers, wood containers, wood flooring, wood trusses, manufactured homes (i.e., mobile home), and prefabricated wood buildings. The production processes of the Wood Product Manufacturing subsector include sawing, planing, shaping, laminating, and assembling of wood products starting from logs that are cut into bolts, or lumber that then may be further cut, or shaped by lathes or other shaping tools. The lumber or other transformed wood shapes may also be subsequently planed or smoothed, and assembled into finished products, such as wood containers. The Wood Product Manufacturing subsector includes establishments that make wood products from logs and bolts that are sawed and shaped, and establishments that purchase sawed lumber and make wood products. With the exception of sawmills and wood preservation establishments, the establishments are grouped into industries mainly based on the specific products manufactured.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>15</Code><Description>Nonmetallic mineral product manufacturing</Description><Definition>The Nonmetallic Mineral Product Manufacturing NAICS subsector transforms mined or quarried nonmetallic minerals, such as sand, gravel, stone, clay, and refractory materials, into products for intermediate or final consumption. Processes used include grinding, mixing, cutting, shaping, and honing. Heat often is used in the process and chemicals are frequently mixed to change the composition, purity, and chemical properties for the intended product. The Nonmetallic Mineral Product Manufacturing subsector includes establishments that manufacture products, such as bricks, refractories, ceramic products, and glass and glass products, such as plate glass and containers. Also included are cement and concrete products, lime, gypsum and other nonmetallic mineral products including abrasive products, ceramic plumbing fixtures, statuary, cut stone products, and mineral wool.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>16</Code><Description>Primary metal manufacturing</Description><Definition>Industries in the Primary Metal Manufacturing NAICS subsector smelt and/or refine ferrous and nonferrous metals from ore, pig or scrap, using electrometallurgical and other process metallurgical techniques. Establishments in this subsector also manufacture metal alloys and superalloys by introducing other chemical elements to pure metals. The output of smelting and refining, usually in ingot form, is used in rolling, drawing, and extruding operations to make sheet, strip, bar, rod, or wire, and in molten form to make castings and other basic metal products.  Primary manufacturing of ferrous and nonferrous metals begins with ore or concentrate as the primary input. Establishments manufacturing primary metals from ore and/or concentrate remain classified in the primary smelting, primary refining, or iron and steel mill, industries regardless of the form of their output. Establishments primarily engaged in secondary smelting and/or secondary refining recover ferrous and nonferrous metals from scrap and/or dross. The output of the secondary smelting and/or secondary refining industries is limited to shapes, such as ingot or billet that will be further processed. Recovery of metals from scrap often occurs in establishments that are primarily engaged in activities, such as rolling, drawing, extruding, or similar processes.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>17</Code><Description>Fabricated metal product manufacturing</Description><Definition>Industries in the Fabricated Metal Product Manufacturing NAICS subsector transform metal into intermediate or end products, other than machinery, computers and electronics, and metal furniture or treat metals and metal formed products fabricated elsewhere. Important fabricated metal processes are forging, stamping, bending, forming, and machining, used to shape individual pieces of metal; and other processes, such as welding and assembling, used to join separate parts together. Establishments in this subsector may use one of these processes or a combination of these processes.  The NAICS structure for this subsector distinguishes the forging and stamping processes in a single industry. The remaining industries, in the subsector, group establishments based on similar combinations of processes used to make products.  The manufacturing performed in the Fabricated Metal Product Manufacturing subsector begins with manufactured metal shapes. The establishments in this sector further fabricate the purchased metal shapes into a product. For instance, the Spring and Wire Product Manufacturing industry starts with wire and fabricates such items.  Within manufacturing there are other establishments that make the same products made by this subsector; only these establishments begin production further back in the production process. These establishments have a more integrated operation. For instance, one establishment may manufacture steel, draw it into wire, and make wire products in the same establishment. Such operations are classified in the Primary Metal Manufacturing subsector.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>18</Code><Description>Machinery manufacturing</Description><Definition>Industries in the Machinery Manufacturing NAICS subsector create end products that apply mechanical force, for example, the application of gears and levers, to perform work. Some important processes for the manufacture of machinery are forging, stamping, bending, forming, and machining that are used to shape individual pieces of metal. Processes, such as welding and assembling are used to join separate parts together. Although these processes are similar to those used in metal fabricating establishments, machinery manufacturing is different because it typically employs multiple metal forming processes in manufacturing the various parts of the machine. Moreover, complex assembly operations are an inherent part of the production process.  In general, design considerations are very important in machinery production. Establishments specialize in making machinery designed for particular applications. Thus, design is considered to be part of the production process for the purpose of implementing NAICS. The NAICS structure reflects this by defining industries and industry groups that make machinery for different applications. A broad distinction exists between machinery that is generally used in a variety of industrial applications (i.e., general purpose machinery) and machinery that is designed to be used in a particular industry (i.e., special purpose machinery). Three industry groups consist of special purpose machinery--Agricultural, Construction, and Mining Machinery Manufacturing; Industrial Machinery Manufacturing; and Commercial and Service Industry Machinery Manufacturing. The other industry groups make general-purpose machinery: Ventilation, Heating, Air Conditioning, and Commercial Refrigeration Equipment Manufacturing; Metalworking Machinery Manufacturing; Engine, Turbine, and Power Transmission Equipment Manufacturing; and Other General Purpose Machinery Manufacturing.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>19</Code><Description>Computer and electronic product manufacturing</Description><Definition>Industries in the Computer and Electronic Product Manufacturing NAICS subsector group establishments that manufacture computers, computer peripherals, communications equipment, and similar electronic products, and establishments that manufacture components for such products. The Computer and Electronic Product Manufacturing industries have been combined in the hierarchy of NAICS because of the economic significance they have attained. Their rapid growth suggests that they will become even more important to the economies of all three North American countries in the future, and in addition their manufacturing processes are fundamentally different from the manufacturing processes of other machinery and equipment. The design and use of integrated circuits and the application of highly specialized miniaturization technologies are common elements in the production technologies of the computer and electronic subsector. Convergence of technology motivates this NAICS subsector. Digitalization of sound recording, for example, causes both the medium (the compact disc) and the equipment to resemble the technologies for recording, storing, transmitting, and manipulating data. Communications technology and equipment have been converging with computer technology. When technologically-related components are in the same sector, it makes it easier to adjust the classification for future changes, without needing to redefine its basic structure. The creation of the Computer and Electronic Product Manufacturing subsector assists in delineating new and emerging industries because the activities that will serve as the probable sources of new industries, such as computer manufacturing and communications equipment manufacturing, or computers and audio equipment are brought together. As new activities emerge, they are less likely therefore, to cross the subsector boundaries of the classification.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>20</Code><Description>Electrical equipment, appliance, and component manufacturing</Description><Definition>Industries in the Electrical Equipment, Appliance, and Component Manufacturing NAICS subsector manufacture products that generate, distribute and use electrical power. Electric Lighting Equipment Manufacturing establishments produce electric lamp bulbs, lighting fixtures, and parts. Household Appliance Manufacturing establishments make both small and major electrical appliances and parts. Electrical Equipment Manufacturing establishments make goods, such as electric motors, generators, transformers, and switchgear apparatus. Other Electrical Equipment and Component Manufacturing establishments make devices for storing electrical power (e.g., batteries), for transmitting electricity (e.g., insulated wire), and wiring devices (e.g., electrical outlets, fuse boxes, and light switches).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>21</Code><Description>Motor vehicles, bodies and trailers, and parts manufacturing</Description><Definition>Motor vehicles, bodies and trailers, and parts manufacturing, a portion of the transportation equipment manufacturing NAICS subsector, is comprised of three NAICS industry groups: motor vehicle manufacturing; motor vehicle body and trailer manufacturing; and motor vehicle parts manufacturing. The motor vehicle manufacturing industry group comprises establishments primarily engaged in (1) manufacturing complete automobile and light duty motor vehicles (i.e., body and chassis or unibody); (2) manufacturing chassis only; (3) manufacturing heavy duty truck chassis and assembling complete heavy duty trucks, buses, heavy duty motor homes, and other special purpose heavy duty motor vehicles for highway use; or (4) manufacturing heavy duty truck chassis only.The motor vehicle body and trailer manufacturing group comprises establishments primarily engaged in (1) manufacturing motor vehicle bodies and cabs or (2) manufacturing truck, automobile and utility trailers, truck trailer chassis, detachable trailer bodies, and detachable trailer chassis. The products made may be sold separately or may be assembled on purchased chassis and sold as complete vehicles. The motor vehicle parts manufacturing industry group comprises establishments primarily engaged in (1) manufacturing and/or rebuilding motor vehicle gasoline engines, and engine parts, whether or not for vehicular use; (2) manufacturing vehicular lighting; (3) manufacturing and/or rebuilding motor vehicle electrical equipment; (4) manufacturing and/or rebuilding motor vehicle steering mechanisms and suspension components (except springs); (5) manufacturing and/or rebuilding motor vehicle brake systems and related components; (6) manufacturing and/or rebuilding motor vehicle transmission and power train parts; (7) manufacturing motor vehicle seating, seats, seat frames, seat belts, and interior trimmings; (8) manufacturing motor vehicle stampings, such as fenders, tops, body parts, trim, and molding; or (9) manufacturing and/or rebuilding motor vehicle parts and accessories.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>22</Code><Description>Other transportation equipment manufacturing</Description><Definition>Transportation equipment manufacturing excluding motor vehicles is comprised of four NAICS industry groups: Aerospace Product and Parts Manufacturing; Railroad Rolling Stock Manufacturing; Ship and Boat Building; and Other Transportation Equipment Manufacturing. Aerospace Product and Parts Manufacturing comprises establishments primarily engaged in one or more of the following: (1) manufacturing complete aircraft, missiles, or space vehicles; (2) manufacturing aerospace engines, propulsion units, auxiliary equipment or parts; (3) developing and making prototypes of aerospace products; (4) aircraft conversion (i.e., major modifications to systems); and (5) complete aircraft or propulsion systems overhaul and rebuilding (i.e., periodic restoration of aircraft to original design specifications). Railroad Rolling Stock Manufacturing comprises establishments primarily engaged in one or more of the following: (1) manufacturing and/or rebuilding locomotives, locomotive frames and parts; (2) manufacturing railroad, street, and rapid transit cars and car equipment for operation on rails for freight and passenger service; and (3) manufacturing rail layers, ballast distributors, rail tamping equipment and other railway track maintenance equipment. Ship and Boat Building comprises establishments primarily engaged in operating shipyards or boat yards (i.e., ship or boat manufacturing facilities). Shipyards are fixed facilities with drydocks and fabrication equipment capable of building a ship, defined as watercraft typically suitable or intended for other than personal or recreational use. Boats are defined as watercraft typically suitable or intended for personal use. Activities of shipyards include the construction of ships, their repair, conversion and alteration, the production of prefabricated ship and barge sections, and specialized services, such as ship scaling. Other Transportation Equipment Manufacturing group comprises establishments primarily engaged in manufacturing motorcycles, bicycles, metal tricycles, complete military armored vehicles, tanks, self-propelled weapons, vehicles pulled by draft animals, and other transportation equipment (except motor vehicles, boats, ships, railroad rolling stock, and aerospace products), including parts thereof.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>23</Code><Description>Furniture and related product manufacturing</Description><Definition>Industries in the Furniture and Related Product Manufacturing NAICS subsector make furniture and related articles, such as mattresses, window blinds, cabinets, and fixtures. The processes used in the manufacture of furniture include the cutting, bending, molding, laminating, and assembly of such materials as wood, metal, glass, plastics, and rattan. However, the production process for furniture is not solely bending metal, cutting and shaping wood, or extruding and molding plastics. Design and fashion trends play an important part in the production of furniture. The integrated design of the article for both esthetic and functional qualities is also a major part of the process of manufacturing furniture. Design services may be performed by the furniture establishment's work force or may be purchased from industrial designers.  Furniture may be made of any material, but the most common ones used in North America are metal and wood. Furniture manufacturing establishments may specialize in making articles primarily from one material. Some of the equipment required to make a wooden table, for example, is different from that used to make a metal one. However, furniture is usually made from several materials. A wooden table might have metal brackets, and a wooden chair a fabric or plastics seat. Therefore, in NAICS, furniture initially is classified based on the type of furniture (application for which it is designed) rather than the material used. For example, an upholstered sofa is treated as household furniture, although it may also be used in hotels or offices.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>24</Code><Description>Miscellaneous manufacturing</Description><Definition>Industries in the Miscellaneous Manufacturing NAICS subsector make a wide range of products that cannot readily be classified in specific NAICS subsectors in manufacturing. Processes used by these establishments vary significantly, both among and within industries. The industries in this subsector are defined by what is made rather than how it is made. Although individual establishments might be appropriately classified elsewhere in the NAICS structure, for historical continuity, these product-based industries were maintained. In most cases, no one process or material predominates for an industry. Establishments in this subsector manufacture products as diverse as medical equipment and supplies, jewelry, sporting goods, toys, and office supplies.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>25</Code><Description>Nondurable goods manufacturing</Description><Definition>Tangible products that can be stored or inventoried and that are usable over a relatively short period. This sub-group of manufacturing is not defined within the SIC or NAICS coding structure.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>26</Code><Description>Food and beverage and tobacco product manufacturing</Description><Definition>This industry includes the NAICS sectors of food manufacturing, and beverage and tobacco product manufacturing.Industries in the Food Manufacturing NAICS subsector transform livestock and agricultural products into products for intermediate or final consumption. The industry groups are distinguished by the raw materials (generally of animal or vegetable origin) processed into food products. The food products manufactured in these establishments are typically sold to wholesalers or retailers for distribution to consumers, but establishments primarily engaged in retailing bakery and candy products made on the premises not for immediate consumption are included.Industries in the Beverage and Tobacco Product Manufacturing NAICS subsector manufacture beverages and tobacco products. The industry group, Beverage Manufacturing, includes three types of establishments: (1) those that manufacture nonalcoholic beverages; (2) those that manufacture alcoholic beverages through the fermentation process; and (3) those that produce distilled alcoholic beverages. Ice manufacturing, while not a beverage, is included with nonalcoholic beverage manufacturing because it uses the same production process as water purification. In the case of activities related to the manufacture of beverages, the structure follows the defined productive processes. Brandy, a distilled beverage, was not placed under distillery product manufacturing, but rather under the NAICS class for winery product manufacturing since the productive process used in the manufacturing of alcoholic grape-based beverages produces both wines (fermented beverage) and brandies (distilled beverage). The industry group, Tobacco Manufacturing, includes two types of establishments: (1) those engaged in redrying and stemming tobacco and (2) those that manufacture tobacco products, such as cigarettes and cigars.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>27</Code><Description>Textile mills and textile product mills</Description><Definition>This sector includes textile mills and textile product mills.Industries in the Textile Mills NAICS subsector group establishments that transform a basic fiber (natural or synthetic) into a product, such as yarn or fabric, that is further manufactured into usable items, such as apparel, sheets, towels, and textile bags for individual or industrial consumption. The further manufacturing may be performed in the same establishment and classified in this subsector, or it may be performed at a separate establishment and be classified elsewhere in manufacturing.Industries in the Textile Product Mills NAICS subsector group establishments that make textile products (except apparel). With a few exceptions, processes used in these industries are generally cut and sew (i.e., purchasing fabric and cutting and sewing to make nonapparel textile products, such as sheets and towels).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>28</Code><Description>Apparel, leather, and allied product manufacturing</Description><Definition>Industries in the Apparel, leather, and allied product manufacturing NAICS subsectors involve three manufacturing processes: (1) cut and sew (i.e., purchasing fabric and cutting and sewing to make a garment), (2) the manufacture of garments in establishments that first knit fabric and then cut and sew the fabric into a garment, and (3) transform hides into leather by tanning or curing and fabricating the leather into products for final consumption (it also includes the manufacture of similar products from other materials, including products made from "leather substitutes," such as rubber, plastics, or textiles). The Apparel Manufacturing subsector includes a diverse range of establishments manufacturing full lines of ready-to-wear apparel and custom apparel: apparel contractors, performing cutting or sewing operations on materials owned by others; jobbers performing entrepreneurial functions involved in apparel manufacture; and tailors, manufacturing custom garments for individual clients are all included. Knitting, when done alone, is classified in the Textile Mills subsector, but when knitting is combined with the production of complete garments, the activity is classified in Apparel Manufacturing. The Leather and Allied Product Manufacturing subsector includes all leather products and products made from "leather substitutes" such as rubber footwear, textile luggage, and plastics purses or wallets. The products made from leather substitutes are included in this subsector because they are made in similar ways leather products are made (e.g., luggage). They are made in the same establishments, so it is not practical to separate them. The inclusion of leather making is partly because leather tanning is a relatively small industry that has few close neighbors as a production process, partly because leather is an input to some of the other products classified in Leather and Allied Products Manufacturing and partly for historical reasons.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>29</Code><Description>Paper manufacturing</Description><Definition>Industries in the Paper Manufacturing NAICS subsector make pulp, paper, or converted paper products. The manufacturing of these products is grouped together because they constitute a series of vertically connected processes. More than one is often carried out in a single establishment. There are essentially three activities. The manufacturing of pulp involves separating the cellulose fibers from other impurities in wood or used paper. The manufacturing of paper involves matting these fibers into a sheet. Converted paper products are made from paper and other materials by various cutting and shaping techniques and includes coating and laminating activities.  The Paper Manufacturing subsector is subdivided into two industry groups, the first for the manufacturing of pulp and paper and the second for the manufacturing of converted paper products. Paper making is treated as the core activity of the subsector. Therefore, any establishment that makes paper (including paperboard), either alone or in combination with pulp manufacturing or paper converting, is classified as a paper or paperboard mill. Establishments that make pulp without making paper are classified as pulp mills. Pulp mills, paper mills and paperboard mills comprise the first industry group. Establishments that make products from purchased paper and other materials make up the second industry group, Converted Paper Product Manufacturing.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>30</Code><Description>Printing and related support activities</Description><Definition>Industries in the Printing and Related Support Activities NAICS subsector print products, such as newspapers, books, labels, business cards, stationery, business forms, and other materials, and perform support activities, such as data imaging, platemaking services, and bookbinding. The support activities included here are an integral part of the printing industry, and a product (a printing plate, a bound book, or a computer disk or file) that is an integral part of the printing industry is almost always provided by these operations.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>31</Code><Description>Petroleum and coal products manufacturing</Description><Definition>The Petroleum and Coal Products Manufacturing NAICS subsector is based on the transformation of crude petroleum and coal into usable products. The dominant process is petroleum refining that involves the separation of crude petroleum into component products through such techniques as cracking and distillation. In addition, this subsector includes establishments that primarily further process refined petroleum and coal products and produce products, such as asphalt coatings and petroleum lubricating oils.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>32</Code><Description>Chemical manufacturing</Description><Definition>The Chemical Manufacturing NAICS subsector is based on the transformation of organic and inorganic raw materials by a chemical process and the formulation of products. This subsector distinguishes the production of basic chemicals that comprise the first industry group from the production of intermediate and end products produced by further processing of basic chemicals that make up the remaining industry groups.  This subsector does not include all industries transforming raw materials by a chemical process. It is common for some chemical processing to occur during mining operations. These beneficiating operations, such as copper concentrating, are classified in Sector 21, Mining. Furthermore, the refining of crude petroleum is included in Subsector 324, Petroleum and Coal Products Manufacturing. In addition, the manufacturing of aluminum oxide is included in Subsector 331, Primary Metal Manufacturing; and beverage distilleries are classified in Subsector 312, Beverage and Tobacco Product Manufacturing. As in the case of these two activities, the grouping of industries into subsectors may take into account the association of the activities performed with other activities in the subsector.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>33</Code><Description>Plastics and rubber products manufacturing</Description><Definition>Industries in the Plastics and Rubber Products Manufacturing NAICS subsector make goods by processing plastics materials and raw rubber. The core technology employed by establishments in this subsector is that of plastics or rubber product production. Plastics and rubber are combined in the same subsector because plastics are increasingly being used as a substitute for rubber; however the subsector is generally restricted to the production of products made of just one material, either solely plastics or rubber.  Many manufacturing activities use plastics or rubber, for example the manufacture of footwear, or furniture. Typically, the production process of these products involves more than one material. In these cases, technologies that allow disparate materials to be formed and combined are of central importance in describing the manufacturing activity. In NAICS, such activities (the footwear and furniture manufacturing) are not classified in the Plastics and Rubber Products Manufacturing subsector because the core technologies for these activities are diverse and involve multiple materials.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>34</Code><Description>Wholesale trade</Description><Definition>The term "wholesale trade" is used in the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:This SIC division includes establishments or places of business primarily engaged in selling merchandise to retailers; to industrial, commercial, institutional, farm, construction contractors, or professional business users; or to other wholesalers; or acting as agents or brokers in buying merchandise for or selling merchandise to such persons or companies. NAICS definition:The Wholesale Trade NAICS sector comprises establishments engaged in wholesaling merchandise, generally without transformation, and rendering services incidental to the sale of merchandise. The merchandise described in this sector includes the outputs of agriculture, mining, manufacturing, and certain information industries, such as publishing.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>35</Code><Description>Retail trade</Description><Definition>The term "retail trade" is used in the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:This SIC division includes establishments engaged in selling merchandise for personal or household consumption and rendering services incidental to the sale of the goods. In general, retail establishments are classified by kind of business according to the principal lines of commodities sold (groceries, hardware, etc.), or the usual trade designation (drug store, cigar store, etc.). Some of the important characteristics of retail trade establishments are: the establishment is usually a place of business and is engaged in activities to attract the general public to buy; the establishment buys or receives merchandise as well as sells; the establishment may process its products, but such processing is incidental or subordinate to selling; the establishment is considered as retail in the trade; and the establishment sells to customers for personal or household use. Not all of these characteristics need be present and some are modified by trade practice. NAICS definition:The Retail Trade NAICS sector comprises establishments engaged in retailing merchandise, generally without transformation, and rendering services incidental to the sale of merchandise. The retailing process is the final step in the distribution of merchandise; retailers are, therefore, organized to sell merchandise in small quantities to the general public. This sector comprises two main types of retailers: store and nonstore retailers. 1. Store retailers operate fixed point-of-sale locations, located and designed to attract a high volume of walk-in customers. In general, retail stores have extensive displays of merchandise and use mass-media advertising to attract customers. They typically sell merchandise to the general public for personal or household consumption, but some also serve business and institutional clients. These include establishments, such as office supply stores, computer and software stores, building materials dealers, plumbing supply stores, and electrical supply stores. Catalog showrooms, gasoline stations, automotive dealers, and mobile home dealers are treated as store retailers. In addition to retailing merchandise, some types of store retailers are also engaged in the provision of after-sales services, such as repair and installation. For example, new automobile dealers, electronic and appliance stores, and musical instrument and supply stores often provide repair services. As a general rule, establishments engaged in retailing merchandise and providing after-sales services are classified in this sector. 2. Nonstore retailers, like store retailers, are organized to serve the general public, but their retailing methods differ. The establishments of this subsector reach customers and market merchandise with methods, such as the broadcasting of "infomercials," the broadcasting and publishing of direct-response advertising, the publishing of paper and electronic catalogs, door-to-door solicitation, in-home demonstration, selling from portable stalls (street vendors, except food), and distribution through vending machines. Establishments engaged in the direct sale (nonstore) of products, such as home heating oil dealers and home delivery newspaper routes are included here.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>36</Code><Description>Transportation and warehousing</Description><Definition>The Transportation and Warehousing NAICS sector includes industries providing transportation of passengers and cargo, warehousing and storage for goods, scenic and sightseeing transportation, and support activities related to modes of transportation. Establishments in these industries use transportation equipment or transportation related facilities as a productive asset. The type of equipment depends on the mode of transportation. The modes of transportation are air, rail, water, road, and pipeline.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>37</Code><Description>Air transportation</Description><Definition>Industries in the Air Transportation NAICS subsector provide air transportation of passengers and/or cargo using aircraft, such as airplanes and helicopters. The subsector distinguishes scheduled from nonscheduled air transportation. Scheduled air carriers fly regular routes on regular schedules and operate even if flights are only partially loaded. Nonscheduled carriers often operate during nonpeak time slots at busy airports. These establishments have more flexibility with respect to choice of airport, hours of operation, load factors, and similar operational characteristics. Nonscheduled carriers provide chartered air transportation of passengers, cargo, or specialty flying services. Specialty flying services establishments use general purpose aircraft to provide a variety of specialized flying services.  Scenic and sightseeing air transportation and air courier services are not included in this subsector but are included in Subsector 487, Scenic and Sightseeing Transportation and in Subsector 492, Couriers and Messengers. Although these activities may use aircraft, they are different from the activities included in air transportation. Air sightseeing does not usually involve place-to-place transportation; the passenger's flight (e.g., balloon ride, aerial sightseeing) typically starts and ends at the same location. Courier services (individual package or cargo delivery) includes more than air transportation; road transportation is usually required to deliver the cargo to the intended recipient.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>38</Code><Description>Rail transportation</Description><Definition>Industries in the Rail Transportation NAICS subsector provide rail transportation of passengers and/or cargo using railroad rolling stock. The railroads in this subsector primarily either operate on networks, with physical facilities, labor force, and equipment spread over an extensive geographic area, or operate over a short distance on a local rail line.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>39</Code><Description>Water transportation</Description><Definition>The term "water transportation" is used in the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:This major group includes establishments engaged in freight and passenger transportation on the open seas or inland waters, and establishments furnishing such incidental services as lighterage, towing, and canal operation. This major group also includes excursion boats, sight-seeing boats, and water taxis. NAICS definition:Industries in the Water Transportation subsector provide water transportation of passengers and cargo using watercraft, such as ships, barges, and boats.Scenic and sightseeing water transportation services are not included in this subsector but are included in Subsector 487, Scenic and Sightseeing Transportation. Although these activities use watercraft, they are different from the activities included in water transportation. Water sightseeing does not usually involve place-to-place transportation; the passenger's trip starts and ends at the same location.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>40</Code><Description>Truck transportation</Description><Definition>Industries in the Truck Transportation NAICS subsector provide over-the-road transportation of cargo using motor vehicles, such as trucks and tractor trailers. The subsector is subdivided into general freight trucking and specialized freight trucking. This distinction reflects differences in equipment used, type of load carried, scheduling, terminal, and other networking services. General freight transportation establishments handle a wide variety of general commodities, generally palletized, and transported in a container or van trailer. Specialized freight transportation is the transportation of cargo that, because of size, weight, shape, or other inherent characteristics require specialized equipment for transportation.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>41</Code><Description>Transit and ground passenger transportation</Description><Definition>Industries in the Transit and Ground Passenger Transportation NAICS subsector include a variety of passenger transportation activities, such as urban transit systems; chartered bus, school bus, and interurban bus transportation; and taxis. These activities are distinguished based primarily on such production process factors as vehicle types, routes, and schedules.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>42</Code><Description>Pipeline transportation</Description><Definition>Industries in the Pipeline Transportation NAICS subsector use transmission pipelines to transport products, such as crude oil, natural gas, refined petroleum products, and slurry. Industries are identified based on the products transported (i.e., pipeline transportation of crude oil, natural gas, refined petroleum products, and other products).  The Pipeline Transportation of Natural Gas industry includes the storage of natural gas because the storage is usually done by the pipeline establishment and because a pipeline is inherently a network in which all the nodes are interdependent.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>43</Code><Description>Other transportation and support activities</Description><Definition>Other Transportation and Support Activities includes scenic and sightseeing transportation, couriers and messengers, and support activities for transportation.Industries in the Scenic and Sightseeing Transportation NAICS subsector utilize transportation equipment to provide recreation and entertainment. These activities have a production process distinct from passenger transportation carried out for the purpose of other types of for-hire transportation. This process does not emphasize efficient transportation; in fact, such activities often use obsolete vehicles, such as steam trains, to provide some extra ambience. The activity is local in nature, usually involving a same-day return to the point of departure. The Scenic and Sightseeing Transportation subsector is separated into three industries based on the mode: land, water, and other. Activities that are recreational in nature and involve participation by the customer, such as white-water rafting, are generally excluded from this subsector, unless they impose an impact on part of the transportation system. Charter boat fishing, for example, is included in the Scenic and Sightseeing Transportation, Water industry.Industries in the Couriers and Messengers NAICS subsector provide intercity and/or local delivery of parcels. These articles can be described as those that may be handled by one person without using special equipment. This allows the collection, pick-up, and delivery operations to be done with limited labor costs and minimal equipment. Sorting and transportation activities, where necessary, are generally mechanized. The restriction to small parcels partly distinguishes these establishments from those in the transportation industries. The complete network of courier services establishments also distinguishes these transportation services from local messenger and delivery establishments in this subsector. This includes the establishments that perform intercity transportation as well as establishments that, under contract to them, perform local pick--up and delivery. Messengers, which usually deliver within a metropolitan or single urban area, may use bicycle, foot, small truck, or van.Industries in the Support Activities for Transportation NAICS subsector provide services which support transportation. These services may be provided to transportation carrier establishments or to the general public. This subsector includes a wide array of establishments, including air traffic control services, marine cargo handling, and motor vehicle towing.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>44</Code><Description>Warehousing and storage</Description><Definition>Industries in the Warehousing and Storage NAICS subsector are primarily engaged in operating warehousing and storage facilities for general merchandise, refrigerated goods, and other warehouse products. These establishments provide facilities to store goods. They do not sell the goods they handle. These establishments take responsibility for storing the goods and keeping them secure. They may also provide a range of services, often referred to as logistics services, related to the distribution of goods. Logistics services can include labeling, breaking bulk, inventory control and management, light assembly, order entry and fulfillment, packaging, pick and pack, price marking and ticketing, and transportation arrangement. However, establishments in this industry group always provide warehousing or storage services in addition to any logistic services. Furthermore, the warehousing or storage of goods must be more than incidental to the performance of services, such as price marking.  Bonded warehousing and storage services and warehouses located in free trade zones are included in the industries of this subsector.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>45</Code><Description>Information</Description><Definition>The Information NAICS sector comprises establishments engaged in the following processes: (a) producing and distributing information and cultural products, (b) providing the means to transmit or distribute these products as well as data or communications, and (c) processing data.  The main components of this sector are the publishing industries, including software publishing, and both traditional publishing and publishing exclusively on the Internet; the motion picture and sound recording industries; the broadcasting industries, including traditional broadcasting and those broadcasting exclusively over the Internet; the telecommunications industries; the industries known as Internet service providers and Web search portals; data processing industries; and the information services industries.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>46</Code><Description>Publishing industries (except Internet)</Description><Definition>Industries in the Publishing Industries (except Internet) NAICS subsector group establishments engaged in the publishing of newspapers, magazines, other periodicals, and books, as well as directory and mailing list and software publishing. In general, these establishments, which are known as publishers, issue copies of works for which they usually possess copyright. Works may be in one or more formats including traditional print form, CD-ROM, or proprietary electronic networks. Publishers may publish works originally created by others for which they have obtained the rights and/or works that they have created in-house. Software publishing is included here because the activity, creation of a copyrighted product and bringing it to market, is equivalent to the creation process for other types of intellectual products.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>47</Code><Description>Motion picture and sound recording industries</Description><Definition>Industries in the Motion Picture and Sound Recording Industries NAICS subsector group establishments involved in the production and distribution of motion pictures and sound recordings. While producers and distributors of motion pictures and sound recordings issue works for sale as traditional publishers do, the processes are sufficiently different to warrant placing establishments engaged in these activities in a separate subsector. Production is typically a complex process that involves several distinct types of establishments that are engaged in activities, such as contracting with performers, creating the film or sound content, and providing technical postproduction services. Film distribution is often to exhibitors, such as theaters and broadcasters, rather than through the wholesale and retail distribution chain. When the product is in a mass-produced form, NAICS treats production and distribution as the major economic activity as it does in the Publishing Industries subsector, rather than as a subsidiary activity to the manufacture of such products.  This subsector does not include establishments primarily engaged in the wholesale distribution of video cassettes and sound recordings, such as compact discs and audio tapes; these establishments are included in the Wholesale Trade sector. Reproduction of video cassettes and sound recordings that is carried out separately from establishments engaged in production and distribution is treated in NAICS as a manufacturing activity.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>48</Code><Description>Broadcasting (except Internet) and telecommunications</Description><Definition>Industries in the Broadcasting (except Internet) and telecommunications subsector include establishments providing point-to-point communications and the services related to that activity. The industry groups (Radio and Television Broadcasting, Cable Networks and Program Distribution, and Telecommunications) are based on differences in the methods of communication and in the nature of services provided.The Radio and Television Broadcasting industry group includes establishments that operate broadcasting studios and facilities for over the air or satellite delivery of radio and television programs of entertainment, news, talk, and the like. These establishments are often engaged in the production and purchase of programs and generating revenues from the sale of air time to advertisers and from donations, subsidies, and/or the sale of programs.The Cable Networks and Program Distribution industry group includes establishments operating studios and facilities for the broadcasting of programs that are typically narrowcast in nature (limited format, such as news, sports, education, and youth-oriented programming) on a subscription or fee basis.The Telecommunications industry group is primarily engaged in operating, maintaining, and/or providing access to facilities for the transmission of voice, data, text, sound, and video. A transmission facility may be based on a single technology or a combination of technologies.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>49</Code><Description>Data processing, hosting, and other information services</Description><Definition>Industries in the Data processing, hosting, and other information services NAICS subsector group establishments that provide: (1) access to the Internet; (2) search facilities for the Internet; and (3) data processing, hosting, and related services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>50</Code><Description>Finance, insurance, real estate, rental, and leasing</Description><Definition>Equal to industries of finance and insurance + real estate, rental, and leasing.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>51</Code><Description>Finance and insurance</Description><Definition>The Finance and Insurance NAICS sector comprises establishments primarily engaged in financial transactions (transactions involving the creation, liquidation, or change in ownership of financial assets) and/or in facilitating financial transactions. Three principal types of activities are identified:  Raising funds by taking deposits and/or issuing securities and, in the process, incurring liabilities. Establishments engaged in this activity use raised funds to acquire financial assets by making loans and/or purchasing securities. Putting themselves at risk, they channel funds from lenders to borrowers and transform or repackage the funds with respect to maturity, scale and risk. This activity is known as financial intermediation.  Pooling of risk by underwriting insurance and annuities. Establishments engaged in this activity collect fees, insurance premiums, or annuity considerations; build up reserves; invest those reserves; and make contractual payments. Fees are based on the expected incidence of the insured risk and the expected return on investment.  Providing specialized services facilitating or supporting financial intermediation, insurance, and employee benefit programs.  In addition, monetary authorities charged with monetary control are included in this sector.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>52</Code><Description>Monetary Authorities- central bank, credit intermediation, and related services</Description><Definition>The Monetary Authorities-Central Bank subsector groups establishments that engage in performing central banking functions, such as issuing currency, managing the Nation's money supply and international reserves, holding deposits that represent the reserves of other banks and other central banks, and acting as fiscal agent for the central government.The Credit Intermediation and Related Activities subsector group establishments that (1) lend funds raised from depositors; (2) lend funds raised from credit market borrowing; or (3) facilitate the lending of funds or issuance of credit by engaging in such activities as mortgage and loan brokerage, clearinghouse and reserve services, and cash checking services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>53</Code><Description>Securities, commodity contracts, and other financial investments and related activities</Description><Definition>Industries in the Securities, Commodity Contracts, and Other Financial Investments and Related Activities NAICS subsector group establishments that are primarily engaged in one of the following: (1) underwriting securities issues and/or making markets for securities and commodities; (2) acting as agents (i.e., brokers) between buyers and sellers of securities and commodities; (3) providing securities and commodity exchange services; and (4) providing other services, such as managing portfolios of assets; providing investment advice; and trust, fiduciary, and custody services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>54</Code><Description>Insurance carriers and related activities</Description><Definition>Industries in the Insurance Carriers and Related Activities NAICS subsector group establishments that are primarily engaged in one of the following (1) underwriting (assuming the risk, assigning premiums, and so forth) annuities and insurance policies or (2) facilitating such underwriting by selling insurance policies, and by providing other insurance and employee-benefit related services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>55</Code><Description>Funds, trusts, and other financial vehicles</Description><Definition>Industries in the Funds, Trusts, and Other Financial Vehicles NAICS subsector are comprised of legal entities (i.e., funds, plans, and/or programs) organized to pool securities or other assets on behalf of shareholders or beneficiaries of employee benefit or other trust funds. The portfolios are customized to achieve specific investment characteristics, such as diversification, risk, rate of return, and price volatility. These entities earn interest, dividends, and other property income, but have little or no employment and no revenue from the sale of services. Establishments with employees devoted to the management of funds are classified in Industry Group 5239, Other Financial Investment Activities.  Establishments primarily engaged in holding the securities of (or other equity interests in) other firms are classified in Sector 55, Management of Companies and Enterprises.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>56</Code><Description>Real estate and rental and leasing</Description><Definition>The Real Estate and Rental and Leasing NAICS sector comprises establishments primarily engaged in renting, leasing, or otherwise allowing the use of tangible or intangible assets, and establishments providing related services. The major portion of this sector comprises establishments that rent, lease, or otherwise allow the use of their own assets by others. The assets may be tangible, as is the case of real estate and equipment, or intangible, as is the case with patents and trademarks. This sector also includes establishments primarily engaged in managing real estate for others, selling, renting and/or buying real estate for others, and appraising real estate. These activities are closely related to this sector's main activity, and it was felt that from a production basis they would best be included here. In addition, a substantial proportion of property management is self-performed by lessors. The main components of this sector are the real estate lessors industries (including equity real estate investment trusts (REITs)); equipment lessors industries (including motor vehicles, computers, and consumer goods); and lessors of nonfinancial intangible assets (except copyrighted works).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>57</Code><Description>Real estate</Description><Definition>The term "real estate" is used in the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:This major group includes real estate operators, and owners and lessors of real property, as well as buyers, sellers, developers, agents, and brokers. NAICS definition:Industries in the Real Estate subsector group establishments that are primarily engaged in renting or leasing real estate to others; managing real estate for others; selling, buying, or renting real estate for others; and providing other real estate related services, such as appraisal services.This subsector includes equity Real Estate Investment Trusts (REITs) that are primarily engaged in leasing buildings, dwellings, or other real estate property to others. Mortgage REITs are classified in Subsector 525, Funds, Trusts, and Other Financial Vehicles.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>58</Code><Description>Rental and leasing services and lessors of nonfinancial intangible assets</Description><Definition>This industry NAICS group includes Rental and Leasing Services combined with Lessors of Nonfinancial Intangible Assets (except Copyrighted Works).Industries in the Rental and Leasing Services NAICS subsector include establishments that provide a wide array of tangible goods, such as automobiles, computers, consumer goods, and industrial machinery and equipment, to customers in return for a periodic rental or lease payment. The subsector includes two main types of establishments: (1) those that are engaged in renting consumer goods and equipment and (2) those that are engaged in leasing machinery and equipment often used for business operations. The first type typically operates from a retail-like or store-front facility and maintains inventories of goods that are rented for short periods of time. The latter type typically does not operate from retail-like locations or maintain inventories, and offers longer term leases. These establishments work directly with clients to enable them to acquire the use of equipment on a lease basis, or they work with equipment vendors or dealers to support the marketing of equipment to their customers under lease arrangements. Equipment lessors generally structure lease contracts to meet the specialized needs of their clients and use their remarketing expertise to find other users for previously leased equipment. Establishments that provide operating and capital (i.e., finance) leases are included in this subsector.Industries in the Lessors of Nonfinancial Intangible Assets (except Copyrighted Works) NAICS subsector include establishments that are primarily engaged in assigning rights to assets, such as patents, trademarks, brand names, and/or franchise agreements for which a royalty payment or licensing fee is paid to the asset holder. Establishments in this subsector own the patents, trademarks, and/or franchise agreements that they allow others to use or reproduce for a fee and may or may not have created those assets.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>59</Code><Description>Professional and business services</Description><Definition>Professional and business services consists of professional and technical services + management of companies and enterprises + administrative and waste services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>60</Code><Description>Professional, scientific, and technical services</Description><Definition>The Professional, Scientific, and Technical Services NAICS sector comprises establishments that specialize in performing professional, scientific, and technical activities for others. These activities require a high degree of expertise and training. The establishments in this sector specialize according to expertise and provide these services to clients in a variety of industries and, in some cases, to households. Activities performed include: legal advice and representation; accounting, bookkeeping, and payroll services; architectural, engineering, and specialized design services; computer services; consulting services; research services; advertising services; photographic services; translation and interpretation services; veterinary services; and other professional, scientific, and technical services.This sector excludes establishments primarily engaged in providing a range of day-to-day office administrative services, such as financial planning, billing and recordkeeping, personnel, and physical distribution and logistics. These establishments are classified in Sector 56, Administrative and Support and Waste Management and Remediation Services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>61</Code><Description>Legal services</Description><Definition>This industry appears in both SIC and NAICS tables. This major SIC group includes establishments which are headed by members of the bar and are engaged in offering legal advice or legal services. The NAICS subsector includes offices of lawyers, offices of notaries, title abstract and settlement offices, and other legal services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>62</Code><Description>Computer systems design and related services</Description><Definition>This industry comprises establishments primarily engaged in providing expertise in the field of information technologies through one or more of the following activities: writing, modifying, testing and supporting software to meet the needs of a particular customer; planning and designing computer systems that integrate computer hardware, software, and communication technologies; on-site management and operation of clients' computer systems and/or data processing facilities; and other professional and technical computer-related advice and services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>63</Code><Description>Miscellaneous professional, scientific, and technical services</Description><Definition>Miscellaneous professional, scientific, and technical services NAICS sector comprises establishments that specialize in performing professional, scientific, and technical activities for others (except legal services and computer systems design). These activities require a high degree of expertise and training. The establishments in this sector specialize according to expertise and provide these services to clients in a variety of industries and, in some cases, to households. Activities performed include: accounting, bookkeeping, and payroll services; architectural, engineering, and specialized design services; consulting services; research services; advertising services; photographic services; translation and interpretation services; veterinary services; and other professional, scientific, and technical services. This sector excludes establishments primarily engaged in providing a range of day-to-day office administrative services, such as financial planning, billing and recordkeeping, personnel, and physical distribution and logistics. These establishments are classified in Administrative and Support and Waste Management and Remediation Services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>64</Code><Description>Management of companies and enterprises</Description><Definition>The Management of Companies and Enterprises NAICS sector comprises (1) establishments that hold the securities of (or other equity interests in) companies and enterprises for the purpose of owning a controlling interest or influencing management decisions or (2) establishments (except government establishments) that administer, oversee, and manage establishments of the company or enterprise and that normally undertake the strategic or organizational planning and decision-making role of the company or enterprise. Establishments that administer, oversee, and manage may hold the securities of the company or enterprise.  Establishments in this sector perform essential activities that are often undertaken, in-house, by establishments in many sectors of the economy. By consolidating the performance of these activities of the enterprise at one establishment, economies of scale are achieved.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>65</Code><Description>Administrative and support and waste management and remediation services</Description><Definition>The Administrative and Support and Waste Management and Remediation Services NAICS sector comprises establishments performing routine support activities for the day-to-day operations of other organizations. These essential activities are often undertaken in-house by establishments in many sectors of the economy. The establishments in this sector specialize in one or more of these support activities and provide these services to clients in a variety of industries and, in some cases, to households. Activities performed include: office administration, hiring and placing of personnel, document preparation and similar clerical services, solicitation, collection, security and surveillance services, cleaning, and waste disposal services.  The administrative and management activities performed by establishments in this sector are typically on a contract or fee basis. These activities may also be performed by establishments that are part of the company or enterprise. However, establishments involved in administering, overseeing, and managing other establishments of the company or enterprise, are classified in Sector 55, Management of Companies and Enterprises. These establishments normally undertake the strategic and organizational planning and decision-making role of the company or enterprise. Government establishments engaged in administering, overseeing, and managing governmental programs are classified in Sector 92, Public Administration.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>66</Code><Description>Administrative and support services</Description><Definition>Industries in the Administrative and Support Services NAICS subsector group establishments engaged in activities that support the day-to-day operations of other organizations. The processes employed in this sector (e.g., general management, personnel administration, clerical activities, cleaning activities) are often integral parts of the activities of establishments found in all sectors of the economy. The establishments classified in this subsector have specialized in one or more of these activities and can, therefore, provide services to clients in a variety of industries and, in some cases, to households. The individual industries of this subsector are defined on the basis of the particular process that they are engaged in and the particular services they provide.  Many of the activities performed in this subsector are ongoing routine support functions that all businesses and organizations must do and that they have traditionally done for themselves. Recent trends, however, are to contract or purchase such services from businesses that specialize in such activities and can, therefore, provide the services more efficiently.  The industries in this subsector cannot be viewed as strictly "support." The Travel Arrangement and Reservation Services industry group, includes travel agents, tour operators, and providers of other travel arrangement services, such as hotel and restaurant reservations and arranging the purchase of tickets, serves many types of clients, including individual consumers. This group was placed in this subsector because the services are often of the "support" nature (e.g., travel arrangement) and businesses and other organizations are increasingly the ones purchasing such services.  The administrative and management activities performed by establishments in this sector are typically on a contract or fee basis. These activities may also be performed by establishments that are part of the company or enterprise. However, establishments involved in administering, overseeing, and managing other establishments of the company or enterprise, are classified in Sector 55, Management of Companies and Enterprises. These establishments normally undertake the strategic and organizational planning and decision-making role of the company or enterprise. Government establishments engaged in administering, overseeing and managing governmental programs are classified in Sector 92, Public Administration.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>67</Code><Description>Waste management and remediation services</Description><Definition>Industries in the Waste Management and Remediation Services NAICS subsector group establishments engaged in the collection, treatment, and disposal of waste materials. This includes establishments engaged in local hauling of waste materials; operating materials recovery facilities (i.e., those that sort recyclable materials from the trash stream); providing remediation services (i.e., those that provide for the cleanup of contaminated buildings, mine sites, soil, or ground water); and providing septic pumping and other miscellaneous waste management services. There are three industry groups within the subsector that separate these activities into waste collection, waste treatment and disposal, and remediation and other waste management.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>68</Code><Description>Educational services, health care, and social assistance</Description><Definition>Consists of educational services and services industries within the health care and social assistance sector.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>69</Code><Description>Educational services</Description><Definition>The term "Educational services" is used in both the SIC and NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems.SIC definition: This SIC major group (82) includes establishments providing academic or technical instruction. Also included are establishments providing educational services such as libraries, student exchange programs, and curriculum development. Schools for the instruction of beauticians and cosmetologists are classified in Industry 7231, and barber colleges are classified in Industry 7241. Establishments primarily engaged in providing job training for the unemployed, the underemployed, the handicapped, and to persons who have a job market disadvantage because of lack of education, job skill or experience are classified in Industry 8331.NAICS definition:The Educational Services (NAICS) sector comprises establishments that provide instruction and training in a wide variety of subjects. This instruction and training is provided by specialized establishments, such as schools, colleges, universities, and training centers. These establishments may be privately owned and operated for profit or not for profit, or they may be publicly owned and operated. They may also offer food and accommodation services to their students. For the public sector, the income and employment are classified by level of government- federal, state, and local. The estimates for the federal government are sub classified into civilian and military. The different treatment of the private and public sectors means that BEA's state and local government industry includes public education, public hospitals, and other types of government services while BEA reports only private schools in its educational services industry corresponding to NAICS code 61 and only private hospitals in its hospitals industry corresponding to NAICS code 622.  Educational services (NAICS) are usually delivered by teachers or instructors that explain, tell, demonstrate, supervise, and direct learning. Instruction is imparted in diverse settings, such as educational institutions, the workplace, or the home through correspondence, television, or other means. It can be adapted to the particular needs of the students, for example sign language can replace verbal language for teaching students with hearing impairments. All industries in the sector share this commonality of process, namely, labor inputs of instructors with the requisite subject matter expertise and teaching ability.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>70</Code><Description>Health care and social assistance</Description><Definition>The Health Care and Social Assistance NAICS sector comprises establishments providing health care and social assistance for individuals. The sector includes both health care and social assistance because it is sometimes difficult to distinguish between the boundaries of these two activities. The industries in this sector are arranged on a continuum starting with those establishments providing medical care exclusively, continuing with those providing health care and social assistance, and finally finishing with those providing only social assistance. The services provided by establishments in this sector are delivered by trained professionals. All industries in the sector share this commonality of process, namely, labor inputs of health practitioners or social workers with the requisite expertise. Many of the industries in the sector are defined based on the educational degree held by the practitioners included in the industry.  Excluded from this sector are aerobic classes in Subsector 713, Amusement, Gambling and Recreation Industries and nonmedical diet and weight reducing centers in Subsector 812, Personal and Laundry Services. Although these can be viewed as health services, these services are not typically delivered by health practitioners.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>71</Code><Description>Ambulatory health care services</Description><Definition>Industries in the Ambulatory Health Care Services NAICS subsector provide health care services directly or indirectly to ambulatory patients and do not usually provide inpatient services. Health practitioners in this subsector provide outpatient services, with the facilities and equipment not usually being the most significant part of the production process.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>72</Code><Description>Hospitals</Description><Definition>Industries in the Hospitals NAICS subsector provide medical, diagnostic, and treatment services that include physician, nursing, and other health services to inpatients and the specialized accommodation services required by inpatients. Hospitals may also provide outpatient services as a secondary activity. Establishments in the Hospitals subsector provide inpatient health services, many of which can only be provided using the specialized facilities and equipment that form a significant and integral part of the production process.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>73</Code><Description>Nursing and residential care facilities</Description><Definition>Industries in the Nursing and Residential Care Facilities NAICS subsector provide residential care combined with either nursing, supervisory, or other types of care as required by the residents. In this subsector, the facilities are a significant part of the production process and the care provided is a mix of health and social services with the health services being largely some level of nursing services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>74</Code><Description>Social assistance</Description><Definition>Industries in the Social Assistance NAICS subsector provide a wide variety of social assistance services directly to their clients. These services do not include residential or accommodation services, except on a short stay basis.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>75</Code><Description>Arts, entertainment, recreation, accommodation, and food services</Description><Definition>Consists of industries within the arts, entertainment, and recreation and accommodation and food services sector. Equal to industries of arts, entertainment, and recreation + accommodation and food services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>76</Code><Description>Arts, entertainment, and recreation</Description><Definition>The Arts, Entertainment, and Recreation NAICS sector includes a wide range of establishments that operate facilities or provide services to meet varied cultural, entertainment, and recreational interests of their patrons. This sector comprises (1) establishments that are involved in producing, promoting, or participating in live performances, events, or exhibits intended for public viewing; (2) establishments that preserve and exhibit objects and sites of historical, cultural, or educational interest; and (3) establishments that operate facilities or provide services that enable patrons to participate in recreational activities or pursue amusement, hobby, and leisure time interests.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>77</Code><Description>Performing arts, spectator sports, museums, and related activities</Description><Definition>This industry group includes the NAICS sectors of performing arts, spectator sports, and related industries; and museums, historical sites, and similar institutions.Industries in the Performing Arts, Spectator Sports, and Related Industries group establishments that produce or organize and promote live presentations involving the performances of actors and actresses, singers, dancers, musical groups and artists, athletes, and other entertainers, including independent (i.e., freelance) entertainers and the establishments that manage their careers. The classification recognizes four basic processes: (1) producing (i.e., presenting) events; (2) organizing, managing, and/or promoting events; (3) managing and representing entertainers; and (4) providing the artistic, creative and technical skills necessary to the production of these live events. Also, this subsector contains four industries for performing arts companies. Each is defined on the basis of the particular skills of the entertainers involved in the presentations. Excluded from this subsector are nightclubs.Industries in the Museums, Historical Sites, and Similar Institutions subsector engage in the preservation and exhibition of objects, sites, and natural wonders of historical, cultural, and/or educational value.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>78</Code><Description>Amusement, gambling, and recreation industries</Description><Definition>Industries in the Amusements, Gambling, and Recreation Industries NAICS subsector operate facilities where patrons can primarily engage in sports, recreation, amusement, or gambling activities and/or provide other amusement and recreation services, such as supplying and servicing amusement devices in places of business operated by others; operating sports teams, clubs, or leagues engaged in playing games for recreational purposes; and guiding tours without using transportation equipment.  The industry groups in this subsector highlight particular types of activities: amusement parks and arcades, gambling industries, and other amusement and recreation industries. The groups, however, are not all inclusive of the activity. The Gambling Industries industry group does not provide for full coverage of gambling activities. For example, casino hotels are classified in Subsector 721, Accommodation; and horse and dog racing tracks are classified in Industry Group 7112, Spectator Sports.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>79</Code><Description>Accommodation and food services</Description><Definition>The Accommodation and Food Services NAICS sector comprises establishments providing customers with lodging and/or preparing meals, snacks, and beverages for immediate consumption. The sector includes both accommodation and food services establishments because the two activities are often combined at the same establishment.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>80</Code><Description>Accommodation</Description><Definition>Industries in the Accommodation NAICS subsector provide lodging or short-term accommodations for travelers, vacationers, and others. There is a wide range of establishments in these industries. Some provide lodging only; while others provide meals, laundry services, and recreational facilities, as well as lodging. Lodging establishments are classified in this subsector even if the provision of complementary services generates more revenue. The types of complementary services provided vary from establishment to establishment. The subsector is organized into three industry groups: (1) traveler accommodation, (2) recreational accommodation, and (3) rooming and boarding houses. The Traveler Accommodation industry group includes establishments that primarily provide traditional types of lodging services. This group includes hotels, motels, and bed and breakfast inns. In addition to lodging, these establishments may provide a range of other services to their guests. The RV (Recreational Vehicle) Parks and Recreational Camps industry group includes establishments that operate lodging facilities primarily designed to accommodate outdoor enthusiasts. Included are travel trailer campsites, recreation vehicle parks, and outdoor adventure retreats. The Rooming and Boarding Houses industry group includes establishments providing temporary or longer-term accommodations that for the period of occupancy may serve as a principal residence. Board (i.e., meals) may be provided but is not essential. Establishments that manage short-stay accommodation establishments (e.g., hotels and motels) on a contractual basis are classified in this subsector if they both manage the operation and provide the operating staff. Such establishments are classified based on the type of facility managed and operated.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>81</Code><Description>Food services and drinking places</Description><Definition>Industries in the Food Services and Drinking Places NAICS subsector prepare meals, snacks, and beverages to customer order for immediate on-premises and off-premises consumption. There is a wide range of establishments in these industries. Some provide food and drink only; while others provide various combinations of seating space, waiter/waitress services and incidental amenities, such as limited entertainment. The industries in the subsector are grouped based on the type and level of services provided. The industry groups are special food services, such as food service contractors, caterers, and mobile food services; drinking places; and restaurants and other eating places.  Food and beverage services at hotels and motels; amusement parks, theaters, casinos, country clubs, and similar recreational facilities; and civic and social organizations are included in this subsector only if these services are provided by a separate establishment primarily engaged in providing food and beverage services.  Excluded from this subsector are establishments operating dinner cruises. These establishments are classified in Subsector 487, Scenic and Sightseeing Transportation because those establishments utilize transportation equipment to provide scenic recreational entertainment.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>82</Code><Description>Other services (except government and government enterprises)</Description><Definition>The Other services (except government and government enterprises) NAICS sector comprises establishments engaged in providing services not specifically provided for elsewhere in the classification system. Establishments in this sector are primarily engaged in activities, such as equipment and machinery repairing, promoting or administering religious activities, grant-making, advocacy, and providing dry-cleaning and laundry services, personal care services, death care services, pet care services, photofinishing services, temporary parking services, and dating services.  Private households that engage in employing workers on or about the premises in activities primarily concerned with the operation of the household are included in this sector.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>83</Code><Description>Government and government enterprises</Description><Definition>Government includes the executive, legislative, judicial, administrative and regulatory activities of Federal, state, and local governments. It includes the military. Government enterprises are government agencies that cover a substantial portion of their operating costs by selling goods and services to the public and that maintain their own separate accounts.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>84</Code><Description>Federal civilian</Description><Definition>A sub-group of "government and government enterprises". Congressional staff and the U.S. Postal Service are included in this category.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>85</Code><Description>Military</Description><Definition>A sub-group of "Government and government enterprises, " this major group includes government establishments primarily engaged in national security and national affairs. The estimates of wages and salaries for the military services consist of cash wages (including allowances) of full-time personnel of the armed services (including the Coast Guard), cash wages of the members of the Reserves including the National Guard, and pay-in-kind received by the full-time and reserve enlisted personnel of the armed services.Military employment is measured as the number of military personnel assigned to active duty units that are stationed in the area plus the number of military reserve unit members. The estimates of active duty employment for the Army, Air Force, Navy, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard are based on the annual averages of 12 monthly observations, for a given year, from reports received from each branch of service. Navy personnel assigned to ships and other mobile units and Marines assigned to Fleet Marine Force units are measured according to the units' home ports rather than their actual locations as of the reporting date. The measure of the employment of the military Reserves--including the National Guard--is confined to members of reserve units that meet regularly for training. The state estimates are based on fiscal year--ending September 30--tabulations of military reserve strength provided by the Department of Defense.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>86</Code><Description>State and local</Description><Definition>"State and local" is a sub-group of Government and government enterprises.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>87</Code><Description>Natural resources and mining</Description><Definition>Natural resources and mining consists of Agriculture, forestry, fishing and hunting; and mining.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>88</Code><Description>Trade</Description><Definition>Trade consists of wholesale and retail trade.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>89</Code><Description>Transportation and utilities</Description><Definition>Transportation and utilities consists of utilities and these transportation industries: air, rail, water, truck, transit and ground passenger, pipeline, other transportation and support activities, and warehousing and storage.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>90</Code><Description>Manufacturing and information</Description><Definition>Consists of the Manufacturing and Information industries. The Manufacturing NAICS sector comprises establishments engaged in the mechanical, physical, or chemical transformation of materials, substances, or components into new products. The assembling of component parts of manufactured products is considered manufacturing, except in cases where the activity is appropriately classified in Sector 23, Construction. Establishments in the Manufacturing sector are often described as plants, factories, or mills and characteristically use power-driven machines and materials-handling equipment. However, establishments that transform materials or substances into new products by hand or in the worker's home and those engaged in selling to the general public products made on the same premises from which they are sold, such as bakeries, candy stores, and custom tailors, may also be included in this sector. Manufacturing establishments may process materials or may contract with other establishments to process their materials for them. Both types of establishments are included in manufacturing. The Information NAICS sector comprises establishments engaged in the following processes: (a) producing and distributing information and cultural products, (b) providing the means to transmit or distribute these products as well as data or communications, and (c) processing data. The main components of this sector are the publishing industries, including software publishing, and both traditional publishing and publishing exclusively on the Internet; the motion picture and sound recording industries; the broadcasting industries, including traditional broadcasting and those broadcasting exclusively over the Internet; the telecommunications industries; the industries known as Internet service providers and Web search portals; data processing industries; and the information services industries.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>91</Code><Description>Private goods-producing industries</Description><Definition>The private goods-producing industries consist of Agriculture, forestry, fishing and hunting; mining; construction; and manufacturing.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>92</Code><Description>Private services-providing industries</Description><Definition>The private services-producing industries consist of utilities; wholesale trade; retail trade; transportation and warehousing, excluding Postal Service; information; finance and insurance; real estate, rental, and leasing; professional, scientific, and technical services; management of companies; administrative and support and waste management and remediation services; educational services; health care and social assistance; arts, entertainment, and recreation; accommodation and food services; and other services (except public administration).</Definition></LINE></TABLE_DEFINITIONS>
