<TABLE_DEFINITIONS Table="SAGDP1" Name="State annual gross domestic product (GDP) summary" Source="USDOC/BEA/RD"><LINE><Code>1</Code><Description>Real GDP (millions of chained 2017 dollars)</Description><Definition>Real GDP by state is an inflation-adjusted measure of each state's gross product that is based on national prices for the goods and services produced within the state. The real estimates of gross domestic product (GDP) by state are measured in chained (2017) dollars (SIC-based statistics are in chained (1997) dollars).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2</Code><Description>Chain-type quantity indexes for real GDP</Description><Definition>A quantity index is an index number that measures the change in the level of a quantity from a base year, apart from any changes in relative prices. The value of the quantity index is 100 for the base year.BEA uses chain-type annual-weighted indexes, also known as Fisher indexes, as its measure of real output and prices. These measures allow for the effects of changes in relative prices and in the composition of output over time, thereby eliminating a major source of bias inherent in fixed-weight indexes.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>3</Code><Description>Current-dollar GDP (millions of current dollars)</Description><Definition>Gross domestic product (GDP) by state is the measure of the market value of all final goods and services produced within a state in a particular period of time. In concept, an industry's GDP by state, referred to as its "value added", is equivalent to its gross output (sales or receipts and other operating income, commodity taxes, and inventory change) minus its intermediate inputs (consumption of goods and services purchased from other U.S. industries or imported). GDP by state is the state counterpart of the Nation's GDP, the Bureau's featured and most comprehensive measure of U.S. economic activity. GDP by state differs from national GDP for the following reason: GDP by state excludes and national GDP includes the compensation of federal civilian and military personnel stationed abroad and government consumption of fixed capital for military structures located abroad and for military equipment, except office equipment.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>4</Code><Description>Compensation (millions of dollars)</Description><Definition>The total remuneration, both monetary and in kind, payable by employers to employees in return for their work during the period. It consists of wages and salaries and of supplements to wages and salaries. Compensation is presented on an accrual basis--that is, it reflects compensation liabilities incurred by the employer in a given period regardless of when the compensation is actually received by the employee.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>5</Code><Description>Gross operating surplus (millions of dollars)</Description><Definition>Gross operating surplus (GOS) is the business income of private domestic enterprises. It includes consumption of fixed capital (CFC), proprietors' income, corporate profits, and business current transfer payments (net).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>6</Code><Description>Taxes on production and imports (TOPI) less subsides (millions of dollars)</Description><Definition>See Subsidies and Taxes on Production and Imports. Contact Gross Domestic Product by State Estimates for more information.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>7</Code><Description>Taxes on production and imports (TOPI) (millions of dollars)</Description><Definition>Taxes on production and imports (TOPI) consist of tax liabilities, such as general sales and property taxes, that are chargeable to business expense in the calculation of profit-type incomes. Also included are special assessments. TOPI is the sum of state and local taxes, primarily nonpersonal property taxes, licenses, and sales and gross receipts taxes, and Federal taxes, which is composed of excise taxes on goods and services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>8</Code><Description>Subsidies (millions of dollars)</Description><Definition>The monetary grants paid by government agencies to private business or to government enterprises at another level of government.</Definition></LINE></TABLE_DEFINITIONS>
