<TABLE_DEFINITIONS Table="SAPCE1" Name="Personal consumption expenditures (PCE) by major type of product" Source="USDOC/BEA/RD"><LINE><Code>1</Code><Description>Personal consumption expenditures</Description><Definition>A measure of spending on goods and services purchased by, and on behalf of, households based on households' state of residence in the fifty states and the District of Columbia.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2</Code><Description>Goods</Description><Definition>Tangible products that can be stored or inventoried.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>3</Code><Description>Durable goods</Description><Definition>Goods that have an average life of at least three years.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>4</Code><Description>Motor vehicles and parts</Description><Definition>Purchases of new motor vehicles, net purchases of used motor vehicles, and purchases of motor vehicle parts and accessories.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>5</Code><Description>Furnishings and durable household equipment</Description><Definition>Purchases of furniture and furnishings, household appliances, glassware, tableware, and household utensils, and tools and equipment for house and garden.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>6</Code><Description>Recreational goods and vehicles</Description><Definition>Purchases of video, audio, photographic, and information processing equipment and media, sporting equipment supplies, guns, and ammunition, sports and recreational vehicles, recreational books, and musical instruments.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>7</Code><Description>Other durable goods</Description><Definition>Purchases of jewelry and watches, therapeutic appliances and equipment, educational books, luggage and similar personal items, and telephone and facsimile equipment.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>8</Code><Description>Nondurable goods</Description><Definition>Goods that have an average life of less than three years.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>9</Code><Description>Food and beverages purchased for off-premises consumption</Description><Definition>Purchases of food and nonalcoholic beverages purchased for off-premises consumption, alcoholic beverages purchased for off-premises consumption, and food produced and consumed on farms.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>10</Code><Description>Clothing and footwear</Description><Definition>Purchases of garments and other clothing materials and footwear. Garments consist of women's and girl's clothing, men's and boy's clothing, and children's and infant's clothing.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>11</Code><Description>Gasoline and other energy goods</Description><Definition>Purchases of motor vehicle fuels, lubricants, and fluids, and fuel oils and other fuels.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>12</Code><Description>Other nondurable goods</Description><Definition>Purchases of pharmaceutical and other medical products, recreational items, household supplies, personal care products, tobacco, and magazines, newspapers, and stationery.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>13</Code><Description>Services</Description><Definition>Products that cannot be stored or inventoried that are usually consumed at the place and time of their purchase.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>14</Code><Description>Household consumption expenditures (for services)</Description><Definition>Consists of actual and imputed consumption expenditures for services by resident households.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>15</Code><Description>Housing and utilities</Description><Definition>Spending on housing and household utilities. Housing consists of the monetary rents paid by tenants for tenant-occupied housing, an imputed rental value for owner-occupied dwellings (measured as the income the homeowner could have received if the house had been rented to a tenant), the rental value of farm dwellings, and spending on group housing. Household utilities consist of water supply and sanitation and electricity and gas.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>16</Code><Description>Health care</Description><Definition>Spending on outpatient services and hospital and nursing home services. Outpatient services consist of physician services, dental services, and paramedical services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>17</Code><Description>Transportation services</Description><Definition>Spending on motor vehicle services and public transportation. Motor vehicle services consist of motor vehicle maintenance and repair and other motor vehicle services. Public transportation consists of ground transportation, air transportation, and water transportation.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>18</Code><Description>Recreation services</Description><Definition>Spending on membership clubs, sports centers, parks, theaters, and museums, audio-video, photographic, and information processing equipment services, gambling, and other recreational services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>19</Code><Description>Food services and accommodations</Description><Definition>Spending on food services and accommodations. Food services consist of purchased meals and beverages and food furnished to employees (including military).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>20</Code><Description>Financial services and insurance</Description><Definition>Spending on financial services and insurance. Financial services consist of financial services furnished without payment, and financial service charges, fees, and commissions. Insurance consists of life insurance, net household insurance, net health insurance, net motor vehicle and other transportation insurance.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>21</Code><Description>Other services</Description><Definition>Spending on communication, education services, professional and other services, personal care and clothing services, social services and religious activities, household maintenance, and net foreign travel.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>22</Code><Description>Final consumption expenditures of nonprofit institutions serving households (NPISHs)</Description><Definition>Net expenses of NPISHs, defined as their gross operating expenses less primary sales to households.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>23</Code><Description>Gross output of nonprofit institutions</Description><Definition>Gross output is net of unrelated sales, secondary sales, and sales to business, government, and the rest of the world; excludes own-account investment (construction and software).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>24</Code><Description>Less: Receipts from sales of goods and services by nonprofit institutions</Description><Definition>Receipts from sales of goods and services by NPISHs. Excludes unrelated sales, secondary sales, and sales to business, government, and the rest of the world; includes membership dues and fees.</Definition></LINE></TABLE_DEFINITIONS>
