<TABLE_DEFINITIONS Table="SASUMMARY" Name="State annual summary statistics: personal income, GDP, consumer spending, price indexes, and employment" Source="USDOC/BEA/RD"><LINE><Code>1</Code><Description>Real GDP (millions of chained 2017 dollars)</Description><Definition>Real GDP by state is an inflation-adjusted measure of each state's gross product that is based on national prices for the goods and services produced within the state. The real estimates of gross domestic product (GDP) by state are measured in chained (2017) dollars.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>2</Code><Description>Real personal income (millions of constant (2017) dollars)</Description><Definition>Real personal income is personal income at RPPs divided by the national PCE price index. It is estimated for states, state metro/nonmetro portions, metropolitan statistical areas, and the combined nonmetropolitan portion of the United States.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>3</Code><Description>Real PCE (millions of constant (2017) dollars)</Description><Definition>Real personal consumption expenditures for states are personal consumption expenditures divided by the RPPs and the national PCE price index. The result is a constant dollar (using 2017 as the base year) estimate of real personal consumption expenditures. Calculations are performed on unrounded data.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>4</Code><Description>Gross domestic product (GDP)</Description><Definition>Gross domestic product (GDP) by state is the measure of the market value of all final goods and services produced within a state in a particular period of time. In concept, an industry's GDP by state, referred to as its "value added", is equivalent to its gross output (sales or receipts and other operating income, commodity taxes, and inventory change) minus its intermediate inputs (consumption of goods and services purchased from other U.S. industries or imported). GDP by state is the state counterpart of the Nation's GDP, the Bureau's featured and most comprehensive measure of U.S. economic activity. GDP by state differs from national GDP for the following reason: GDP by state excludes and national GDP includes the compensation of federal civilian and military personnel stationed abroad and government consumption of fixed capital for military structures located abroad and for military equipment, except office equipment.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>5</Code><Description>Personal income</Description><Definition>Consists of the income that persons receive in return for their provision of labor, land, and capital used in current production as well as other income, such as personal current transfer receipts. In the state and local personal income accounts the personal income of an area represents the income received by or on behalf of the persons residing in that area. It is calculated as the sum of wages and salaries, supplements to wages and salaries, proprietors' income with inventory valuation (IVA) and capital consumption adjustments (CCAdj), rental income of persons with capital consumption adjustment (CCAdj), personal dividend income, personal interest income, and personal current transfer receipts, less contributions for government social insurance plus the adjustment for residence.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>6</Code><Description>Disposable personal income</Description><Definition>The income available to persons for spending or saving. It is equal to personal income less personal current taxes.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>7</Code><Description>Personal consumption expenditures</Description><Definition>A measure of spending on goods and services purchased by, and on behalf of, households based on households' state of residence in the fifty states and the District of Columbia.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>8</Code><Description>Real per capita personal income</Description><Definition>Real per capita personal income is the real personal income divided by midyear population.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>9</Code><Description>Real per capita PCE</Description><Definition>Real per capita personal consumption expenditures is total real personal consumption expenditures divided by total midyear population.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>10</Code><Description>Per capita personal income</Description><Definition>The personal income of a given area divided by the resident population of the area. See "personal income."</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>11</Code><Description>Per capita disposable personal income</Description><Definition>Disposable personal income of a given area divided by the resident population of the area. See "disposable personal income."</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>12</Code><Description>Per capita personal consumption expenditures (PCE)</Description><Definition>Personal consumption expenditures of a given area divided by the resident population of the area. See "personal consumption expenditures."</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>13</Code><Description>Regional price parities (RPPs)</Description><Definition>Regional price parities (RPPs) are regional price levels expressed as a percentage of the overall national price level for a given year. The price levels are determined by the average prices paid by consumers for the mix of goods and services consumed in each region. Taking the ratio of RPPs shows the difference in price levels across regions. RPPs are estimated for states, state metro/nonmetro portions, metropolitan statistical areas, and the combined nonmetropolitan portion of the United States.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>14</Code><Description>Implicit regional price deflator</Description><Definition>The Implicit Regional Price Deflator (IRPD) equals the product of the region's RPP and the U.S. PCE price index. For state PCE, this equals the ratio of the current-dollar value to its corresponding constant-dollar value, multiplied by 100.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>15</Code><Description>Total employment (number of jobs)</Description><Definition>A count of jobs, both full-time and part-time. It includes wage and salary jobs, sole proprietorships, and individual general partners, but not unpaid family workers nor volunteers.</Definition></LINE></TABLE_DEFINITIONS>
