<TABLE_DEFINITIONS Table="SAINC5H" Name="Personal income by major component and earnings by industry (historical)" Source="USDOC/BEA/RD"><LINE><Code>10</Code><Description>Personal income (thousands of dollars)</Description><Definition>Consists of the income that persons receive in return for their provision of labor, land, and capital used in current production as well as other income, such as personal current transfer receipts. In the state and local personal income accounts the personal income of an area represents the income received by or on behalf of the persons residing in that area. It is calculated as the sum of wages and salaries, supplements to wages and salaries, proprietors' income with inventory valuation (IVA) and capital consumption adjustments (CCAdj), rental income of persons with capital consumption adjustment (CCAdj), personal dividend income, personal interest income, and personal current transfer receipts, less contributions for government social insurance plus the adjustment for residence.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>20</Code><Description>Population (persons)</Description><Definition>The number of individuals (both civilian and military) who reside in a given area.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>30</Code><Description>Per capita personal income (dollars)</Description><Definition>The personal income of a given area divided by the resident population of the area. See "personal income."</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>35</Code><Description>Total earnings</Description><Definition>Earnings is the sum of three components of personal income--wages and salaries, supplements to wages and salaries, and proprietors' income. It can be used in the analyses of regional economies as a proxy for the income that is generated from participation in current production. Earnings estimates for 1929-47 are assumed to be on a place-of-residence basis; explicit adjustments were made for the principal interstate commuting flows. "Net earnings" is also presented: This measure is calculated as earnings less contributions for government social insurance plus an adjustment to convert earnings from a place of work to a place of residence basis. The sum of net earnings, personal current transfer receipts, and personal dividend income, personal interest income, and rental income of persons is used in the presentation of state and local area personal income.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>36</Code><Description>Less: Contributions for government social insurance</Description><Definition>Consists of all contributions for government social insurance (by employers, employees, self-employed persons, and by other individuals).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>37</Code><Description>Employee and self-employed contributions for government social insurance</Description><Definition>Consists of the contributions, or payments, by employees, by the self-employed, and by other individuals who participate in the following government programs: old-age, survivors, and disability insurance (Social Security); hospital insurance (Medicare Part A); supplementary medical insurance (Medicare Parts B and D); unemployment insurance; railroad retirement; veterans' life insurance; and temporary disability insurance.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>38</Code><Description>Employer contributions for government social insurance</Description><Definition>Consists of employer payments under the following federal, state, and local government programs: old-age, survivors, and disability insurance; hospital insurance; unemployment insurance; railroad retirement; pension benefit guaranty; veterans' life insurance; publicly administered workers' compensation; military medical insurance; and temporary disability insurance.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>42</Code><Description>Plus: Adjustment for residence</Description><Definition>An adjustment made to those components of earnings and employee contributions to social insurance programs (income subject to adjustment) that are reported on a place-of-work basis to convert them to a place-of-residence basis reflecting the net flow of income of interarea commuters. For example, the source data for wages and salaries represent the wages paid by the establishments located in an area. The wages and salaries that the establishments of a given area pay to workers who live outside that area are treated as an outflow and the wages and salaries that the residents of that area receive from establishments located outside that area are treated as an inflow. The adjustment for residence for an area, then, is the net of the inflows to that area and the outflows from that area.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>45</Code><Description>Equals: Net earnings by place of residence</Description><Definition>Consists of earnings by place of work less contributions for government social insurance plus the adjustment for residence.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>46</Code><Description>Plus: Dividends, interest, and rent</Description><Definition>Consists of personal dividend income, personal interest income, and rental income of persons with capital consumption adjustment (CCAdj).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>47</Code><Description>Plus: Personal current transfer receipts</Description><Definition>Receipts of persons from government and business for which no current services are performed. Current transfer receipts from government include Social Security benefits, medical benefits, veterans' benefits, and unemployment insurance benefits. Current transfer receipts from business include liability payments for personal injury and corporate gifts to nonprofit institutions.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>50</Code><Description>Wages and salaries</Description><Definition>The remuneration receivable by employees (including corporate officers) from employers for the provision of labor services. It includes commissions, tips, and bonuses; employee gains from exercising stock options; and pay-in-kind. Judicial fees paid to jurors and witnesses are classified as wages and salaries. Wages and salaries are measured before deductions, such as social security contributions, union dues, and voluntary employee contributions to defined contribution pension plans.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>60</Code><Description>Supplements to wages and salaries</Description><Definition>Consists of employer contributions for government social insurance and employer contributions for employee pension and insurance funds.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>61</Code><Description>Employer contributions for employee pension and insurance funds</Description><Definition>Consists of employer payments to private and government pension plans and to private insurance funds such as for group health and life insurance; workers' compensation; and supplemental unemployment insurance.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>62</Code><Description>Employer contributions for government social insurance</Description><Definition>Consists of employer payments under the following federal, state, and local government programs: old-age, survivors, and disability insurance; hospital insurance; unemployment insurance; railroad retirement; pension benefit guaranty; veterans' life insurance; publicly administered workers' compensation; military medical insurance; and temporary disability insurance.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>70</Code><Description>Proprietors' income</Description><Definition>Proprietors' income with inventory valuation and capital consumption adjustments is the current-production income (including income in kind) of sole proprietorships, partnerships, and tax-exempt cooperatives. Corporate directors' fees are included in proprietors' income. Proprietors' income includes the interest income received by financial partnerships and the net rental real estate income of those partnerships primarily engaged in the real estate business.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>71</Code><Description>Farm proprietors' income</Description><Definition>Farm proprietors' income consists of the income that is received by the sole proprietorships and the partnerships that operate farms. It excludes the income that is received by corporate farms.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>72</Code><Description>Nonfarm proprietors' income</Description><Definition>Nonfarm Proprietors' Income consists of the income that is received by nonfarm sole proprietorships and partnerships and the income that is received by tax-exempt cooperatives.  The national estimates of nonfarm proprietors' income are primarily derived from income tax data. Because these data do not always reflect current production and because they are incomplete, the estimates also include four major adjustments--the inventory valuation adjustment, the capital consumption adjustment, the "misreporting" adjustment, and the adjustment for the net margins on owner-built housing. The inventory valuation adjustment offsets the effects of the gains and the losses that result from changes in the prices of products withdrawn from inventories; this adjustment for recent years has been small, but it is important to the definition of proprietors' income. The capital consumption adjustment changes the value of the consumption, or depreciation, of fixed capital from the historical-cost basis used in the source data to a replacement-cost basis. The "misreporting" adjustment adds an estimate of the income of sole proprietors and partnerships that is not reported on tax returns. The adjustment for the net margins on owner-built housing is an addition to the estimate for the construction industry. It is the imputed net income of individuals from the construction or renovation of their own dwellings.  The source data necessary to prepare these adjustments are available only at the national level. Therefore, the national estimates of nonfarm proprietors' income that include the adjustments are allocated to states, and these state estimates are allocated to the counties, in proportion to tax return data that do not reflect the adjustments.  In addition, the national estimates include adjustments made to reflect decreases in monetary and imputed income that result from damage to fixed capital and to inventories that is caused by disasters, such as hurricanes, floods, and earthquakes. These adjustments are attributed to states and counties on the basis of information from the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>81</Code><Description>Farm earnings</Description><Definition>Farm labor and proprietors' income is comprised of the net income of sole proprietors, partners, and hired laborers arising directly from the current production of agricultural commodities, either livestock or crops. It includes net farm proprietors' income and the wages and salaries, pay-in-kind, and other labor income of hired farm laborers; but specifically excludes the income of farm corporations.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>82</Code><Description>Nonfarm earnings</Description><Definition>Nonfarm Earnings is the sum of wages and salaries, supplements to wages and salaries, and proprietors' income for all industries, excluding farm.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>90</Code><Description>Private nonfarm earnings</Description><Definition>Private nonfarm earnings is the sum of wages and salaries, supplements to wages and salaries, and nonfarm proprietors' income, excluding farm and government.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>100</Code><Description>Agricultural services, forestry, and fishing</Description><Definition>This SIC division includes establishments primarily engaged in agricultural services, forestry, commercial fishing, hunting, trapping, and related services.The classification of agricultural services includes establishments primarily engaged in supplying soil preparation services, crop services, veterinary services, other animal services, farm labor and management services, and landscape and horticultural services, for others on a contract or fee basis.The classification of forestry covers establishments primarily engaged in the operation of timber tracts, tree farms, forest nurseries, and related activities such as the gathering of gums, barks, balsam needles, maple sap, Spanish moss, and other forest products. Logging establishments are classified in Manufacturing, Industry 2411.The classification of fishing, hunting, and trapping covers establishments primarily engaged in commercial fishing (including crabbing, lobstering, clamming, oystering, and the gathering of sponges and seaweed), and the operation of fish hatcheries and fish and game preserves, in commercial hunting and trapping, and in game propagation.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>200</Code><Description>Mining</Description><Definition>This SIC division includes all establishments primarily engaged in mining. The term mining is used in the broad sense to include the extraction of minerals occurring naturally: solids, such as coal and ores; liquids, such as crude petroleum; and gases such as natural gas. The term mining is also used in the broad sense to include quarrying, well operations, milling (e.g., crushing, screening, washing, flotation), and other preparation customarily done at the mine site, or as a part of mining activity. Exploration and development of mineral properties are included. Services performed on a contract or fee basis in the development or operation of mineral properties are classified separately but within this division. Establishments which have complete responsibility for operating mines, quarries, or oil and gas wells for others on a contract or fee basis are classified according to the product mined rather than as mineral services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>300</Code><Description>Construction</Description><Definition>The term "construction" is used in both the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:This SIC division includes establishments primarily engaged in construction. The term construction includes new work, additions, alterations, reconstruction, installations, and repairs. Construction activities are generally administered or managed from a relatively fixed place of business, but the actual construction work is performed at one or more different sites. If a company has more than one relatively fixed place of business from which it undertakes or manages construction activities and for which separate data on the number of employees, payroll, receipts, and other establishment-type records are maintained, each such place of business is considered a separate construction establishment. Three broad types of construction activity are covered: (1) building construction by general contractors or by operative builders; (2) heavy construction other than building by general contractors and special trade contractors; and (3) construction activity by other special trade contractors. NAICS definition:The construction (NAICS) sector comprises establishments primarily engaged in the construction of buildings or engineering projects (e.g., highways an utility systems). Establishments primarily engaged in the preparation of sites for new construction and establishments primarily engaged in subdividing land for sale as building sites also are included in this sector. Construction work done may include new work, additions, alterations, or maintenance and repairs. Activities of these establishments generally are managed at a fixed place of business, but they usually perform construction activities at multiple project sites. Production responsibilities in this sector are usually specified in (1) contracts with the owners of construction projects (prime contracts) or (2) contracts with other construction establishments (subcontracts).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>400</Code><Description>Manufacturing</Description><Definition>The term "Manufacturing" is used in both the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:The manufacturing SIC division includes establishments engaged in the mechanical or chemical transformation of materials or substances into new products. These establishments are usually described as plants, factories, or mills and characteristically use power driven machines and materials handling equipment. Establishments engaged in assembling component parts of manufactured products are also considered manufacturing if the new product is neither a structure nor other fixed improvement. Also included is the blending of materials, such as lubricating oils, plastics resins, or liquors. NAICS definition:The Manufacturing NAICS sector comprises establishments engaged in the mechanical, physical, or chemical transformation of materials, substances, or components into new products. The assembling of component parts of manufactured products is considered manufacturing, except in cases where the activity is appropriately classified in Sector 23, Construction. Establishments in the Manufacturing sector are often described as plants, factories, or mills and characteristically use power-driven machines and materials-handling equipment. However, establishments that transform materials or substances into new products by hand or in the worker's home and those engaged in selling to the general public products made on the same premises from which they are sold, such as bakeries, candy stores, and custom tailors, may also be included in this sector. Manufacturing establishments may process materials or may contract with other establishments to process their materials for them. Both types of establishments are included in manufacturing.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>500</Code><Description>Transportation and public utilities</Description><Definition>This SIC division includes establishments providing, to the general public or to other business enterprises, passenger and freight transportation, communications services, or electricity, gas, steam, water or sanitary services. For many of the industries in this division, the establishments have activities, workers, and physical facilities distributed over an extensive geographic area. For this division, the establishment is represented by a relatively permanent office, shop, station, terminal, or warehouse, etc. that is either (1) directly responsible for supervising such activities or (2) the base from which personnel operate to carry out these activities. This division is referred to as "Transportation, Communications, Electric, Gas, and Sanitary Services" in the Standard Industrial Classification Manual.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>600</Code><Description>Wholesale and retail trade</Description><Definition>Wholesale and retail trade are combined for estimates before 1958. See also Wholesale trade and Retail trade.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>700</Code><Description>Finance, insurance, and real estate</Description><Definition>This SIC division includes establishments operating primarily in the fields of finance, insurance, and real estate. Finance includes depository institutions, non-depository credit institutions, holding (but not predominantly operating) companies, other investment companies, brokers and dealers in securities and commodity contracts, and security and commodity exchanges. Insurance covers carriers of all types of insurance, and insurance agents and brokers. Real estate includes owners, lessors, lessees, buyers, sellers, agents, and developers of real estate. Establishments primarily engaged in the construction of buildings for sale (operative builders) are classified in Construction, Industry 1531</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>800</Code><Description>Services</Description><Definition>This (SIC) division includes establishments primarily engaged in providing a wide variety of services for individuals, business and government establishments, and other organizations. Hotels and other lodging places; establishments providing personal, business, repair, and amusement services; health, legal, engineering, and other professional services; educational institutions; membership organizations, and other miscellaneous services, are included. Establishments which provide specialized services closely allied to activities covered in other divisions are classified in such divisions.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>900</Code><Description>Government and government enterprises</Description><Definition>Government includes the executive, legislative, judicial, administrative and regulatory activities of Federal, state, and local governments. It includes the military. Government enterprises are government agencies that cover a substantial portion of their operating costs by selling goods and services to the public and that maintain their own separate accounts.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>910</Code><Description>Federal civilian</Description><Definition>A sub-group of "government and government enterprises". Congressional staff and the U.S. Postal Service are included in this category.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>920</Code><Description>Military</Description><Definition>A sub-group of "Government and government enterprises, " this major group includes government establishments primarily engaged in national security and national affairs. The estimates of wages and salaries for the military services consist of cash wages (including allowances) of full-time personnel of the armed services (including the Coast Guard), cash wages of the members of the Reserves including the National Guard, and pay-in-kind received by the full-time and reserve enlisted personnel of the armed services.Military employment is measured as the number of military personnel assigned to active duty units that are stationed in the area plus the number of military reserve unit members. The estimates of active duty employment for the Army, Air Force, Navy, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard are based on the annual averages of 12 monthly observations, for a given year, from reports received from each branch of service. Navy personnel assigned to ships and other mobile units and Marines assigned to Fleet Marine Force units are measured according to the units' home ports rather than their actual locations as of the reporting date. The measure of the employment of the military Reserves--including the National Guard--is confined to members of reserve units that meet regularly for training. The state estimates are based on fiscal year--ending September 30--tabulations of military reserve strength provided by the Department of Defense.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>930</Code><Description>State and local</Description><Definition>"State and local" is a sub-group of Government and government enterprises.</Definition></LINE></TABLE_DEFINITIONS>
