<TABLE_DEFINITIONS Table="SAINC7H" Name="Wages and salaries by industry (historical)" Source="USDOC/BEA/RD"><LINE><Code>50</Code><Description>Wages and salaries (thousands of dollars)</Description><Definition>The remuneration receivable by employees (including corporate officers) from employers for the provision of labor services. It includes commissions, tips, and bonuses; employee gains from exercising stock options; and pay-in-kind. Judicial fees paid to jurors and witnesses are classified as wages and salaries. Wages and salaries are measured before deductions, such as social security contributions, union dues, and voluntary employee contributions to defined contribution pension plans.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>81</Code><Description>Farm wages and salaries</Description><Definition>Farm wages and salaries are comprised of the cash wages and pay-in-kind of hired laborers directly involved in the production of agricultural commodities, either livestock or crops. It includes the salaries received by the owner-operators of farm sole proprietorships, partnerships, and family held corporations.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>82</Code><Description>Nonfarm wages and salaries</Description><Definition>Nonfarm wages and salaries is wages and salaries minus farm wages and salaries.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>90</Code><Description>Private nonfarm wages and salaries</Description><Definition>Private nonfarm wages and salaries is wages and salaries excluding farm and government.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>100</Code><Description>Agricultural services, forestry, and fishing</Description><Definition>This SIC division includes establishments primarily engaged in agricultural services, forestry, commercial fishing, hunting, trapping, and related services.The classification of agricultural services includes establishments primarily engaged in supplying soil preparation services, crop services, veterinary services, other animal services, farm labor and management services, and landscape and horticultural services, for others on a contract or fee basis.The classification of forestry covers establishments primarily engaged in the operation of timber tracts, tree farms, forest nurseries, and related activities such as the gathering of gums, barks, balsam needles, maple sap, Spanish moss, and other forest products. Logging establishments are classified in Manufacturing, Industry 2411.The classification of fishing, hunting, and trapping covers establishments primarily engaged in commercial fishing (including crabbing, lobstering, clamming, oystering, and the gathering of sponges and seaweed), and the operation of fish hatcheries and fish and game preserves, in commercial hunting and trapping, and in game propagation.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>200</Code><Description>Mining</Description><Definition>This SIC division includes all establishments primarily engaged in mining. The term mining is used in the broad sense to include the extraction of minerals occurring naturally: solids, such as coal and ores; liquids, such as crude petroleum; and gases such as natural gas. The term mining is also used in the broad sense to include quarrying, well operations, milling (e.g., crushing, screening, washing, flotation), and other preparation customarily done at the mine site, or as a part of mining activity. Exploration and development of mineral properties are included. Services performed on a contract or fee basis in the development or operation of mineral properties are classified separately but within this division. Establishments which have complete responsibility for operating mines, quarries, or oil and gas wells for others on a contract or fee basis are classified according to the product mined rather than as mineral services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>300</Code><Description>Construction</Description><Definition>The term "construction" is used in both the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:This SIC division includes establishments primarily engaged in construction. The term construction includes new work, additions, alterations, reconstruction, installations, and repairs. Construction activities are generally administered or managed from a relatively fixed place of business, but the actual construction work is performed at one or more different sites. If a company has more than one relatively fixed place of business from which it undertakes or manages construction activities and for which separate data on the number of employees, payroll, receipts, and other establishment-type records are maintained, each such place of business is considered a separate construction establishment. Three broad types of construction activity are covered: (1) building construction by general contractors or by operative builders; (2) heavy construction other than building by general contractors and special trade contractors; and (3) construction activity by other special trade contractors. NAICS definition:The construction (NAICS) sector comprises establishments primarily engaged in the construction of buildings or engineering projects (e.g., highways an utility systems). Establishments primarily engaged in the preparation of sites for new construction and establishments primarily engaged in subdividing land for sale as building sites also are included in this sector. Construction work done may include new work, additions, alterations, or maintenance and repairs. Activities of these establishments generally are managed at a fixed place of business, but they usually perform construction activities at multiple project sites. Production responsibilities in this sector are usually specified in (1) contracts with the owners of construction projects (prime contracts) or (2) contracts with other construction establishments (subcontracts).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>400</Code><Description>Manufacturing</Description><Definition>The term "Manufacturing" is used in both the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:The manufacturing SIC division includes establishments engaged in the mechanical or chemical transformation of materials or substances into new products. These establishments are usually described as plants, factories, or mills and characteristically use power driven machines and materials handling equipment. Establishments engaged in assembling component parts of manufactured products are also considered manufacturing if the new product is neither a structure nor other fixed improvement. Also included is the blending of materials, such as lubricating oils, plastics resins, or liquors. NAICS definition:The Manufacturing NAICS sector comprises establishments engaged in the mechanical, physical, or chemical transformation of materials, substances, or components into new products. The assembling of component parts of manufactured products is considered manufacturing, except in cases where the activity is appropriately classified in Sector 23, Construction. Establishments in the Manufacturing sector are often described as plants, factories, or mills and characteristically use power-driven machines and materials-handling equipment. However, establishments that transform materials or substances into new products by hand or in the worker's home and those engaged in selling to the general public products made on the same premises from which they are sold, such as bakeries, candy stores, and custom tailors, may also be included in this sector. Manufacturing establishments may process materials or may contract with other establishments to process their materials for them. Both types of establishments are included in manufacturing.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>500</Code><Description>Transportation and public utilities</Description><Definition>This SIC division includes establishments providing, to the general public or to other business enterprises, passenger and freight transportation, communications services, or electricity, gas, steam, water or sanitary services. For many of the industries in this division, the establishments have activities, workers, and physical facilities distributed over an extensive geographic area. For this division, the establishment is represented by a relatively permanent office, shop, station, terminal, or warehouse, etc. that is either (1) directly responsible for supervising such activities or (2) the base from which personnel operate to carry out these activities. This division is referred to as "Transportation, Communications, Electric, Gas, and Sanitary Services" in the Standard Industrial Classification Manual.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>600</Code><Description>Wholesale and retail trade</Description><Definition>Wholesale and retail trade are combined for estimates before 1958. See also Wholesale trade and Retail trade.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>700</Code><Description>Finance, insurance, and real estate</Description><Definition>This SIC division includes establishments operating primarily in the fields of finance, insurance, and real estate. Finance includes depository institutions, non-depository credit institutions, holding (but not predominantly operating) companies, other investment companies, brokers and dealers in securities and commodity contracts, and security and commodity exchanges. Insurance covers carriers of all types of insurance, and insurance agents and brokers. Real estate includes owners, lessors, lessees, buyers, sellers, agents, and developers of real estate. Establishments primarily engaged in the construction of buildings for sale (operative builders) are classified in Construction, Industry 1531</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>800</Code><Description>Services</Description><Definition>This (SIC) division includes establishments primarily engaged in providing a wide variety of services for individuals, business and government establishments, and other organizations. Hotels and other lodging places; establishments providing personal, business, repair, and amusement services; health, legal, engineering, and other professional services; educational institutions; membership organizations, and other miscellaneous services, are included. Establishments which provide specialized services closely allied to activities covered in other divisions are classified in such divisions.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>900</Code><Description>Government and government enterprises</Description><Definition>Government includes the executive, legislative, judicial, administrative and regulatory activities of Federal, state, and local governments. It includes the military. Government enterprises are government agencies that cover a substantial portion of their operating costs by selling goods and services to the public and that maintain their own separate accounts.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>910</Code><Description>Federal civilian</Description><Definition>A sub-group of "government and government enterprises". Congressional staff and the U.S. Postal Service are included in this category.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>920</Code><Description>Military</Description><Definition>A sub-group of "Government and government enterprises, " this major group includes government establishments primarily engaged in national security and national affairs. The estimates of wages and salaries for the military services consist of cash wages (including allowances) of full-time personnel of the armed services (including the Coast Guard), cash wages of the members of the Reserves including the National Guard, and pay-in-kind received by the full-time and reserve enlisted personnel of the armed services.Military employment is measured as the number of military personnel assigned to active duty units that are stationed in the area plus the number of military reserve unit members. The estimates of active duty employment for the Army, Air Force, Navy, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard are based on the annual averages of 12 monthly observations, for a given year, from reports received from each branch of service. Navy personnel assigned to ships and other mobile units and Marines assigned to Fleet Marine Force units are measured according to the units' home ports rather than their actual locations as of the reporting date. The measure of the employment of the military Reserves--including the National Guard--is confined to members of reserve units that meet regularly for training. The state estimates are based on fiscal year--ending September 30--tabulations of military reserve strength provided by the Department of Defense.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>930</Code><Description>State and local</Description><Definition>"State and local" is a sub-group of Government and government enterprises.</Definition></LINE></TABLE_DEFINITIONS>
