<TABLE_DEFINITIONS Table="SAINC7S" Name="Wages and salaries by SIC industry" Source="USDOC/BEA/RD"><LINE><Code>50</Code><Description>Wages and salaries by place of work (thousands of dollars)</Description><Definition>The remuneration receivable by employees (including corporate officers) from employers for the provision of labor services. It includes commissions, tips, and bonuses; employee gains from exercising stock options; and pay-in-kind. Judicial fees paid to jurors and witnesses are classified as wages and salaries. Wages and salaries are measured before deductions, such as social security contributions, union dues, and voluntary employee contributions to defined contribution pension plans.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>81</Code><Description>Farm wages and salaries</Description><Definition>Farm wages and salaries are comprised of the cash wages and pay-in-kind of hired laborers directly involved in the production of agricultural commodities, either livestock or crops. It includes the salaries received by the owner-operators of farm sole proprietorships, partnerships, and family held corporations.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>82</Code><Description>Nonfarm wages and salaries</Description><Definition>Nonfarm wages and salaries is wages and salaries minus farm wages and salaries.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>90</Code><Description>Private nonfarm wages and salaries</Description><Definition>Private nonfarm wages and salaries is wages and salaries excluding farm and government.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>100</Code><Description>Agricultural services, forestry, and fishing</Description><Definition>This SIC division includes establishments primarily engaged in agricultural services, forestry, commercial fishing, hunting, trapping, and related services.The classification of agricultural services includes establishments primarily engaged in supplying soil preparation services, crop services, veterinary services, other animal services, farm labor and management services, and landscape and horticultural services, for others on a contract or fee basis.The classification of forestry covers establishments primarily engaged in the operation of timber tracts, tree farms, forest nurseries, and related activities such as the gathering of gums, barks, balsam needles, maple sap, Spanish moss, and other forest products. Logging establishments are classified in Manufacturing, Industry 2411.The classification of fishing, hunting, and trapping covers establishments primarily engaged in commercial fishing (including crabbing, lobstering, clamming, oystering, and the gathering of sponges and seaweed), and the operation of fish hatcheries and fish and game preserves, in commercial hunting and trapping, and in game propagation.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>110</Code><Description>Agricultural services</Description><Definition>Agricultural Services (SIC) includes establishments primarily engaged in performing soil preparation services, crop services, veterinary services, other animal services, farm labor and management services, and landscape and horticultural services, for others on a contract or fee basis.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>120</Code><Description>Forestry and fishing</Description><Definition>This SIC division includes establishments primarily engaged in forestry, commercial fishing, hunting and trapping, and related services.The classification of agricultural services includes establishments primarily engaged in supplying soil preparation services, crop services, landscape and horticultural services, veterinary and other animal services, and farm labor and management services.The classification of forestry covers establishments primarily engaged in the operation of timber tracts, tree farms, or forest nurseries; in the gathering of forest products; or in performing forestry services. Logging establishments are classified in Manufacturing, Industry 2411.The classification of fishing and hunting and trapping covers establishments primarily engaged in commercial fishing (including shellfish and marine products); in operating fish hatcheries and fish and game preserves; and in commercial hunting and trapping.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>121</Code><Description>Forestry</Description><Definition>The term "Forestry" is used in both the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same meaning in both systems. SIC definition: This major group includes establishments primarily engaged in the operation of timber tracts, tree farms, forest nurseries, and related activities such as reforestation services and the gathering of gums, barks, balsam needles, maple sap, Spanish moss, and other forest products. NAICS definition:  Industries in the Forestry and Logging subsector grow and harvest timber on a long production cycle (i.e., of 10 years or more). Long production cycles use different production processes than short production cycles, which require more horticultural interventions prior to harvest, resulting in processes more similar to those found in the Crop Production subsector. Consequently, Christmas tree production and other production involving production cycles of less than 10 years, are classified in the Crop Production subsector.  Industries in this subsector specialize in different stages of the production cycle. Reforestation requires production of seedlings in specialized nurseries. Timber production requires natural forest or suitable areas of land that are available for a long duration. The maturation time for timber depends upon the species of tree, the climatic conditions of the region, and the intended purpose of the timber. The harvesting of timber (except when done on an extremely small scale) requires specialized machinery unique to the industry. Establishments gathering forest products, such as gums, barks, balsam needles, rhizomes, fibers, Spanish moss, and ginseng and truffles, are also included in this subsector.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>122</Code><Description>Fishing</Description><Definition>The term "Fishing" is used in both the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same meaning in both systems. SIC definition:The fishing, hunting, and trapping major group includes establishments primarily engaged in commercial fishing (including crabbing, lobstering, clamming, oystering, and the gathering of sponges and seaweed), and the operation of fish hatcheries and fish and game preserves, in commercial hunting and trapping, and in game propagation. NAICS definition:Industries in the fishing, hunting, and trapping subsector harvest fish and other wild animals from their natural habitats and are dependent upon a continued supply of the natural resource. The harvesting of fish is the predominant economic activity of this subsector and it usually requires specialized vessels that, by the nature of their size, configuration and equipment, are not suitable for any other type of production, such as transportation.Hunting and trapping activities utilize a wide variety of production processes and are classified in the same subsector as fishing because the availability of resources and the constraints imposed, such as conservation requirements and proper habitat maintenance, are similar.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>200</Code><Description>Mining</Description><Definition>This SIC division includes all establishments primarily engaged in mining. The term mining is used in the broad sense to include the extraction of minerals occurring naturally: solids, such as coal and ores; liquids, such as crude petroleum; and gases such as natural gas. The term mining is also used in the broad sense to include quarrying, well operations, milling (e.g., crushing, screening, washing, flotation), and other preparation customarily done at the mine site, or as a part of mining activity. Exploration and development of mineral properties are included. Services performed on a contract or fee basis in the development or operation of mineral properties are classified separately but within this division. Establishments which have complete responsibility for operating mines, quarries, or oil and gas wells for others on a contract or fee basis are classified according to the product mined rather than as mineral services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>210</Code><Description>Metal mining</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments primarily engaged in mining, developing mines, or exploring for metallic minerals (ores). These ores are valued chiefly for the metals contained, to be recovered for use as such or as constituents of alloys, chemicals, pigments or other products. This major group also includes all ore dressing and beneficiating operations, whether performed at mills operated in conjunction with the mines served or at mills, such as custom mills, operated separately. These include mills which crush, grind, wash, dry, sinter, calcine, or leach ore, or perform gravity separation or flotation operations.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>220</Code><Description>Coal mining</Description><Definition>This SIC major group includes establishments primarily engaged in producing bituminous coal, anthracite, and lignite. Included are mining operations and preparation plants (also known as cleaning plants and washeries), whether or not such plants are operated in conjunction with mine sites. The production of coal fuel briquettes and packaged fuel is classified in Manufacturing Industry 2999. Establishments primarily engaged in the production of gas and hydrocarbon liquids from coal at the mine site are classified in Major Group 13.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>230</Code><Description>Oil and gas extraction</Description><Definition>The category "Oil and gas extraction" is used in both the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems.SIC definition:This major SIC group includes establishments primarily engaged in: (1) producing crude petroleum and natural gas; (2) extracting oil from oil sands and oil shale; (3) producing natural gasoline and cycle condensate; and (4) producing gas and hydrocarbon liquids form coal at the mine site. Types of activities included are exploration, drilling, oil and gas well operation and maintenance, the operation of natural gasoline and cycle plants, and the gasification, liquefaction, and pyrolysis of coal at the mine site. This major group also includes such basic activities as emulsion breaking and desilting of crude petroleum in the preparation of oil and gas customarily done at the field site. NAICS definition:Industries in the Oil and Gas Extraction NAICS subsector operate and/or develop oil and gas field properties. Such activities may include exploration for crude petroleum and natural gas; drilling, completing, and equipping wells; operating separators, emulsion breakers, desilting equipment, and field gathering lines for crude petroleum and natural gas; and all other activities in the preparation of oil and gas up to the point of shipment from the producing property. This subsector includes the production of crude petroleum, the mining and extraction of oil from oil shale and oil sands, and the production of natural gas, sulfur recovery from natural gas, and recovery of hydrocarbon liquids.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>240</Code><Description>Nonmetallic minerals, except fuels</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments primarily engaged in mining or quarrying, developing mines, or exploring for nonmetallic minerals, except fuels. Also included are certain well and brine operations, and primary preparation plants, such as those engaged in crushing, grinding, washing, or other concentration.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>300</Code><Description>Construction</Description><Definition>The term "construction" is used in both the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:This SIC division includes establishments primarily engaged in construction. The term construction includes new work, additions, alterations, reconstruction, installations, and repairs. Construction activities are generally administered or managed from a relatively fixed place of business, but the actual construction work is performed at one or more different sites. If a company has more than one relatively fixed place of business from which it undertakes or manages construction activities and for which separate data on the number of employees, payroll, receipts, and other establishment-type records are maintained, each such place of business is considered a separate construction establishment. Three broad types of construction activity are covered: (1) building construction by general contractors or by operative builders; (2) heavy construction other than building by general contractors and special trade contractors; and (3) construction activity by other special trade contractors. NAICS definition:The construction (NAICS) sector comprises establishments primarily engaged in the construction of buildings or engineering projects (e.g., highways an utility systems). Establishments primarily engaged in the preparation of sites for new construction and establishments primarily engaged in subdividing land for sale as building sites also are included in this sector. Construction work done may include new work, additions, alterations, or maintenance and repairs. Activities of these establishments generally are managed at a fixed place of business, but they usually perform construction activities at multiple project sites. Production responsibilities in this sector are usually specified in (1) contracts with the owners of construction projects (prime contracts) or (2) contracts with other construction establishments (subcontracts).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>310</Code><Description>General building contractors</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes general contractors and operative builders primarily engaged in the construction of residential, farm, industrial, commercial, or other buildings. General building contractors who combine a special trade with the contracting are included in this major group.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>320</Code><Description>Heavy construction contractors</Description><Definition>This major SIC group includes general contractors primarily engaged in heavy construction other than building, such as highways and streets, bridges, sewers, railroads, irrigation projects, flood control projects and marine construction, and special trade contractors primarily engaged in activities of a type that are clearly specialized to such heavy construction and are not normally performed on buildings or building-related projects. Specialized activities that are covered here include grading for highways and airport runways; guardrail construction; installation of highway signs; trenching; underwater rock removal; and asphalt and concrete construction of roads, highways, streets, and public sidewalks.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>330</Code><Description>Special trade contractors</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes special trade contractors who undertake activities of a type that are specialized either to building construction, including work on mobile homes, or to both building and nonbuilding projects. These activities include painting (including bridge painting and traffic lane painting), electrical work (including work on bridges, power lines, and power plants), carpentry work, plumbing, heating, air-conditioning, roofing, and sheet metal work.Special trade contractors may work on subcontract from the general contractor, performing only part of the work covered by the general contract, or they may work directly for the owner. Special trade contractors for the most part perform their work at the site of construction, although they also may have shops where they perform work incidental to the job site.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>400</Code><Description>Manufacturing</Description><Definition>The term "Manufacturing" is used in both the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:The manufacturing SIC division includes establishments engaged in the mechanical or chemical transformation of materials or substances into new products. These establishments are usually described as plants, factories, or mills and characteristically use power driven machines and materials handling equipment. Establishments engaged in assembling component parts of manufactured products are also considered manufacturing if the new product is neither a structure nor other fixed improvement. Also included is the blending of materials, such as lubricating oils, plastics resins, or liquors. NAICS definition:The Manufacturing NAICS sector comprises establishments engaged in the mechanical, physical, or chemical transformation of materials, substances, or components into new products. The assembling of component parts of manufactured products is considered manufacturing, except in cases where the activity is appropriately classified in Sector 23, Construction. Establishments in the Manufacturing sector are often described as plants, factories, or mills and characteristically use power-driven machines and materials-handling equipment. However, establishments that transform materials or substances into new products by hand or in the worker's home and those engaged in selling to the general public products made on the same premises from which they are sold, such as bakeries, candy stores, and custom tailors, may also be included in this sector. Manufacturing establishments may process materials or may contract with other establishments to process their materials for them. Both types of establishments are included in manufacturing.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>410</Code><Description>Durable goods manufacturing</Description><Definition>Consists primarily of tangible products that can be stored or inventoried and that can be used repeatedly or continuously over a prolonged period. This sub-group of manufacturing is not defined within the SIC or NAICS coding structure.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>413</Code><Description>Lumber and wood products</Description><Definition>This major SIC group includes establishments engaged in cutting timber and pulpwood; merchant sawmills, lath mills, shingle mills, cooperage stock mills, planing mills, and plywood mills and veneer mills engaged in producing lumber and wood basic materials; and establishments engaged in manufacturing finished articles made entirely or mainly of wood or related materials.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>417</Code><Description>Furniture and fixtures</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments engaged in manufacturing household, office, public building, and restaurant furniture; and office and store fixtures. Establishments primarily engaged in the production of millwork are classified in Industry 2431; those manufacturing wood kitchen cabinets are classified in Industry 2434; those manufacturing cut stone and concrete furniture are classified in Major Group 32; those manufacturing laboratory and hospital furniture, except hospital beds, are classified in Major Group 38; those manufacturing beauty and barber shop furniture are classified in Major Group 39; and those engaged in woodworking to individual order or in the nature of reconditioning and repair are classified in nonmanufacturing industries.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>420</Code><Description>Stone, clay, and glass products</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments engaged in manufacturing flat glass and other glass products, cement, structural clay products, pottery, concrete and gypsum products, cut stone, abrasive and asbestos products, and other products from materials taken principally from the earth in the form of stone, clay, and sand. When separate reports are available for mines and quarries operated by manufacturing establishments classified in this major group, the mining and quarrying activities are classified in Division B, Mining. When separate reports are not available, the mining and quarrying activities, other than those of Industry 3295, are classified herein with the manufacturing operations.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>423</Code><Description>Primary metal industries</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments engaged in smelting and refining ferrous and nonferrous metals from ore, pig, or scrap; in rolling, drawing, and alloying metals; in manufacturing castings and other basic metal products; and in manufacturing nails, spikes, and insulated wire and cable. This major group includes the production of coke.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>426</Code><Description>Fabricated metal products</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group included establishments engaged in fabricating ferrous and nonferrous metal products, such as metal cans, tinware, hand tools, cutlery, general hardware, nonelectric heating apparatus, fabricated structural metal products, metal forgings, metal stampings, ordnance (except vehicles and guided missiles), and a variety of metal and wire products, not elsewhere classified.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>429</Code><Description>Industrial machinery and equipment</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments engaged in manufacturing industrial and commercial machinery and equipment and computers. Included are the manufacture of engines and turbines; farm and garden machinery; construction, mining, and oil field machinery; elevators and conveying equipment; hoists, cranes, monorails, and industrial trucks and tractors; metalworking machinery; special industry machinery; general industrial machinery; computer and peripheral equipment and office machinery; and refrigeration and service industry machinery. Machines powered by built-in or detachable motors ordinarily are included in this major group , with the exception of electrical household appliances. Power-driven hand tools are included in this group, whether electric or otherwise driven.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>432</Code><Description>Electronic and other electric equipment</Description><Definition>The Electronic and Other Electrical Equipment major SIC group includes establishments engaged in manufacturing machinery, apparatus, and supplies for the generation, storage, transmission, transformation, a and utilization of electrical energy. Included are the manufacturing of electricity distribution equipment; electrical industrial apparatus; household appliances; electrical lighting and wiring equipment; radio and television receiving equipment; communications equipment; electronic components and accessories; and other electrical equipment and supplies. The manufacture of household appliances is included in this group, but industrial machinery and equipment powered by built-in or detachable electric motors is classified in Major Group 35. Establishments primarily engaged in manufacturing instruments are classified in Major Group 38. This is a shortened name for Electronic and Other Electrical Equipment and Components, Except Computer Equipment.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>435</Code><Description>Motor vehicles and equipment</Description><Definition>This portion of the transportation equipment major (SIC) group includes establishments engaged in manufacturing or assembling complete passenger automobiles, trucks, commercial cares and buses, and special purpose motor vehicles which are for highway use. It includes Industry Group 3711, Motor Vehicles and Passenger Car Bodies, Industry Group 3713, Truck and Bus Bodies, Industry Group 3714, Motor Vehicle Parts and Accessories, Industry Group 3715, Truck Trailers, and Industry Group 3716, Motor Homes.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>438</Code><Description>Other transportation equipment</Description><Definition>This portion of the transportation equipment major SIC group include establishments engaged in manufacturing equipment for transportation of passengers and cargo by land, air, and water, excluding motor vehicles and motor vehicle equipment. Important products produced by establishments classified in this major group include aircraft, guided missiles and space vehicles, ships, boats, railroad equipment, and miscellaneous transportation equipment, such as motorcycles, bicycles, and snowmobiles.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>441</Code><Description>Instruments and related products</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments engaged in manufacturing instruments (including professional and scientific) for measuring, testing, analyzing, and controlling, and their associated sensors and accessories; optical instruments and lenses; surveying and drafting instruments; hydrological, hydrographic, meteorological, and geophysical equipment; search, detection, navigation, and guidance systems and equipment; surgical, medical, and dental instruments, equipment, and supplies; ophthalmic goods; photographic equipment and supplies; and watches and clocks.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>444</Code><Description>Miscellaneous manufacturing industries</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments primarily engaged in manufacturing products not classified in any other manufacturing major group. Industries in this group fall into the following categories: jewelry, silverware, and plated ware; musical instruments; dolls, toys, fame, and sporting and athletic goods; pens, pencils, and artists' materials; buttons, costume novelties, miscellaneous notions; brooms and brushes; caskets; and other miscellaneous manufacturing industries.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>447</Code><Description>Ordnance</Description><Definition>This major SIC (1967) group includes establishments engaged in manufacturing artillery, small arms, and related equipment; ammunition; tanks and specialized tank parts; sighting and fire control equipment; and miscellaneous ordnance and accessories, not elsewhere classified.Under the 1972 SIC, ordnance was reclassified to four 2-digit industries: Fabricated metal products, electronic and other electric equipment, transportation equipment, and instruments and related products.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>450</Code><Description>Nondurable goods manufacturing</Description><Definition>Tangible products that can be stored or inventoried and that are usable over a relatively short period. This sub-group of manufacturing is not defined within the SIC or NAICS coding structure.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>453</Code><Description>Food and kindred products</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments manufacturing or processing foods and beverages for human consumption, and certain related products, such as manufactured ice, chewing gum, vegetable and animal fats and oils, and prepared feeds for animals and fowls. Products that are described as dietetic are classified in the same manner as nondietetic products (e.g., as candy, canned fruits, cookies).</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>456</Code><Description>Tobacco products</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments engaged in manufacturing cigarettes, cigars, smoking and chewing tobacco, snuff, and reconstituted tobacco and in stemming and redrying tobacco. Also included in this major group is the manufacture of nontobacco cigarettes.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>459</Code><Description>Textile mill products</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments engaged in performing any of the following operations: (1) preparation of fiber and subsequent manufacturing of yarn, thread, braids, twine, and cordage; (2) manufacturing broadwoven fabrics, narrow woven fabrics, knit fabrics, and carpets and rugs from yarn; (3) dyeing and finishing fiber, yarn, fabrics, and knit apparel; (4) coating, waterproofing, or otherwise treating fabrics; (5) the integrated manufacture of knit apparel and other finished articles from yarn; and (6) the manufacture of felt goods, lace goods, nonwoven fabrics, and miscellaneous textiles.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>462</Code><Description>Apparel and other textile products</Description><Definition>This major SIC group, known as the cutting-up and needle trades, includes establishments producing clothing and fabricating products by cutting and sewing purchased woven or knit textiles fabrics and related materials, such as leather, rubberized fabrics, plastics, and furs. Also included are establishments that manufacture clothing by cutting and joining materials such as paper and nonwoven textiles. Included in the apparel industries are three types of establishments: (1) the regular or inside factories; (2) contract factories; and (3) apparel jobbers. The regular factories perform all of the usual manufacturing functions within their own plant; the contract factories manufacture apparel from materials owned by others, and apparel jobbers perform the entrepreneurial functions of a manufacturing company, such as buying raw materials, designing and preparing samples, arranging for the manufacture of clothing from their materials, and selling of finished apparel.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>465</Code><Description>Paper and allied products</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments primarily engaged in the manufacture of pulps from wood and other cellulose fibers, and from rags; the manufacture of paper and paperboard; and the manufacture of paper and paperboard into converted products, such as paper coated off the paper machine, paper bags, paper boxes, and envelopes. Also included are establishments primarily engaged in manufacturing bags of plastics film and sheet.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>468</Code><Description>Printing and publishing</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments engaged in printing by one or more common processes, such as letterpress; lithography (including offset), gravure, or screen; and those establishments which perform services for the printing trade, such as bookbinding and platemaking. This major group also includes establishments engaged in publishing newspapers, books, and periodicals, regardless of whether or not they do their own printing. News syndicates are classified in Services, Industry 7383.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>471</Code><Description>Chemicals and allied products</Description><Definition>This SIC major group includes establishments producing basic chemicals, and establishments manufacturing products by predominantly chemical processes. Establishments classified in this major group manufacture three general classes of products: (1) basic chemicals, such as acids, alkalis, salts, and organic chemicals; (2) chemical products to be used in further manufacture, such as synthetic fibers, plastic materials, dry colors, and pigments; and (3) finished chemical products to be used for ultimate consumption, such as drugs, cosmetics, and soaps; or to be used as materials or supplies in other industries, such as paints, fertilizers, and explosives. The mining of natural alkalis and other natural potassium, sodium, and boron compounds, of natural rock salt, and of other natural chemicals and fertilizers are classified in Mining, Industry Group 147.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>474</Code><Description>Petroleum and coal products</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments primarily engaged in petroleum refining, manufacturing paving and roofing materials, and compounding lubricating oils and greases from purchased materials.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>477</Code><Description>Rubber and miscellaneous plastics products</Description><Definition>This major SIC group includes establishments manufacturing products, not elsewhere classified, from plastics resins and from natural, synthetic, or reclaimed rubber, gutta percha, balata, or gutta siak. Numerous products made from these materials are included in other major groups, such as boats in Major Group 37, and toys, buckles, and buttons in Major Group 39. This group includes establishments primarily manufacturing tires, but establishments primarily recapping and retreading automobile tires are classified in services, Industry 7534. Establishments primarily engaged in manufacturing synthetic rubber and synthetic plastics resins are classified in Industry Group 282.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>480</Code><Description>Leather and leather products</Description><Definition>This major SIC group includes establishments engaged in tanning, currying, and finishing hides and skins, leather converters, and establishments manufacturing finished leather and artificial leather products and some similar products made of other materials.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>500</Code><Description>Transportation and public utilities</Description><Definition>This SIC division includes establishments providing, to the general public or to other business enterprises, passenger and freight transportation, communications services, or electricity, gas, steam, water or sanitary services. For many of the industries in this division, the establishments have activities, workers, and physical facilities distributed over an extensive geographic area. For this division, the establishment is represented by a relatively permanent office, shop, station, terminal, or warehouse, etc. that is either (1) directly responsible for supervising such activities or (2) the base from which personnel operate to carry out these activities. This division is referred to as "Transportation, Communications, Electric, Gas, and Sanitary Services" in the Standard Industrial Classification Manual.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>510</Code><Description>Railroad transportation</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments furnishing transportation by line-haul railroad, and switching and terminal establishments.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>520</Code><Description>Trucking and warehousing</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments furnishing local or long-distance trucking or transfer services, or those engaged in the storage of farm products, furniture and other household goods, or commercial goods of any nature. The operation of terminal facilities for handling freight, with or without maintenance facilities, is also included.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>530</Code><Description>Water transportation</Description><Definition>The term "water transportation" is used in the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:This major group includes establishments engaged in freight and passenger transportation on the open seas or inland waters, and establishments furnishing such incidental services as lighterage, towing, and canal operation. This major group also includes excursion boats, sight-seeing boats, and water taxis. NAICS definition:Industries in the Water Transportation subsector provide water transportation of passengers and cargo using watercraft, such as ships, barges, and boats.Scenic and sightseeing water transportation services are not included in this subsector but are included in Subsector 487, Scenic and Sightseeing Transportation. Although these activities use watercraft, they are different from the activities included in water transportation. Water sightseeing does not usually involve place-to-place transportation; the passenger's trip starts and ends at the same location.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>540</Code><Description>Other transportation</Description><Definition>Other transportation consists of: Local and interurban passenger transitTransportation by airPipelines, except natural gas and Transportation services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>541</Code><Description>Local and interurban passenger transit</Description><Definition>This major SIC group includes establishments primarily engaged in furnishing local and suburban passenger transportation, such as those providing passenger transportation within a single municipality, contiguous municipalities, or a municipality and its suburban areas, by bus, rail, or subway, either separately or in combination, and establishments engaged in furnishing transportation to local scenic features. Also included are establishments primarily engaged in furnishing highway passenger transportation and establishments furnishing highway passenger terminal or maintenance facilities. Intercity bus lines are included in this major group, but interurban railways are classified in Major Group 40.This is a shortened name for the 1987 SIC Major Group 41: Local And Suburban Transit And Interurban Highway Passenger Transportation.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>542</Code><Description>Transportation by air</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments engaged in furnishing domestic and foreign transportation by air and also those operating airports and flying fields and furnishing terminal services. Establishments primarily engaged in performing services which may incidentally use airplanes (e.g., crop dusting and aerial photography) are classified according to the service performed.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>543</Code><Description>Pipelines, except natural gas</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments primarily engaged in the pipeline transportation of petroleum and other commodities, except natural gas. Pipelines operated by petroleum producing or refining companies and separately reported are included.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>544</Code><Description>Transportation services</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments furnishing services incidental to transportation, such as forwarding and packing services, and the arrangement of passenger and freight transportation.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>560</Code><Description>Communications</Description><Definition>This SIC major group includes establishments furnishing point-to-point communications services, whether intended to be received aurally or visually; and radio and television broadcasting. This major group also includes establishments primarily engaged in providing paging and beeper services and those engaged in leasing telephone lines or other methods of telephone transmission, such as optical fiber lines and microwave or satellite facilities, and reselling the use of such methods to others.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>570</Code><Description>Electric, gas, and sanitary services</Description><Definition>This major SIC group includes establishments engaged in the generation, transmission, and/or distribution of electricity or gas or steam. Such establishers may be combinations of any of the above three services and also include other types of services, such as transportation, communications, and refrigeration. Water and irrigation systems, and sanitary systems engaged in the collection and disposal of garbage, sewage, and other wastes by means of destroying or processing materials, are also included. If one service of a combination system does not constitute 95 percent or more of revenues, the establishment should be classified as a combination industry in Industry Group 493, with the subgroup being determined by the major service supplied.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>610</Code><Description>Wholesale trade</Description><Definition>The term "wholesale trade" is used in the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:This SIC division includes establishments or places of business primarily engaged in selling merchandise to retailers; to industrial, commercial, institutional, farm, construction contractors, or professional business users; or to other wholesalers; or acting as agents or brokers in buying merchandise for or selling merchandise to such persons or companies. NAICS definition:The Wholesale Trade NAICS sector comprises establishments engaged in wholesaling merchandise, generally without transformation, and rendering services incidental to the sale of merchandise. The merchandise described in this sector includes the outputs of agriculture, mining, manufacturing, and certain information industries, such as publishing.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>620</Code><Description>Retail trade</Description><Definition>The term "retail trade" is used in the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:This SIC division includes establishments engaged in selling merchandise for personal or household consumption and rendering services incidental to the sale of the goods. In general, retail establishments are classified by kind of business according to the principal lines of commodities sold (groceries, hardware, etc.), or the usual trade designation (drug store, cigar store, etc.). Some of the important characteristics of retail trade establishments are: the establishment is usually a place of business and is engaged in activities to attract the general public to buy; the establishment buys or receives merchandise as well as sells; the establishment may process its products, but such processing is incidental or subordinate to selling; the establishment is considered as retail in the trade; and the establishment sells to customers for personal or household use. Not all of these characteristics need be present and some are modified by trade practice. NAICS definition:The Retail Trade NAICS sector comprises establishments engaged in retailing merchandise, generally without transformation, and rendering services incidental to the sale of merchandise. The retailing process is the final step in the distribution of merchandise; retailers are, therefore, organized to sell merchandise in small quantities to the general public. This sector comprises two main types of retailers: store and nonstore retailers. 1. Store retailers operate fixed point-of-sale locations, located and designed to attract a high volume of walk-in customers. In general, retail stores have extensive displays of merchandise and use mass-media advertising to attract customers. They typically sell merchandise to the general public for personal or household consumption, but some also serve business and institutional clients. These include establishments, such as office supply stores, computer and software stores, building materials dealers, plumbing supply stores, and electrical supply stores. Catalog showrooms, gasoline stations, automotive dealers, and mobile home dealers are treated as store retailers. In addition to retailing merchandise, some types of store retailers are also engaged in the provision of after-sales services, such as repair and installation. For example, new automobile dealers, electronic and appliance stores, and musical instrument and supply stores often provide repair services. As a general rule, establishments engaged in retailing merchandise and providing after-sales services are classified in this sector. 2. Nonstore retailers, like store retailers, are organized to serve the general public, but their retailing methods differ. The establishments of this subsector reach customers and market merchandise with methods, such as the broadcasting of "infomercials," the broadcasting and publishing of direct-response advertising, the publishing of paper and electronic catalogs, door-to-door solicitation, in-home demonstration, selling from portable stalls (street vendors, except food), and distribution through vending machines. Establishments engaged in the direct sale (nonstore) of products, such as home heating oil dealers and home delivery newspaper routes are included here.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>621</Code><Description>Building materials and garden equipment</Description><Definition>The major SIC group Building Material and Garden Equipment includes retail establishments primarily engaged in selling lumber and other building materials; paint, glass, and wallpaper; hardware; nursery stock; lawn and garden supplies; and mobile homes.  It includes lumber and other building materials dealers and paint, glass, and wallpaper stores selling to the general public, even if sales to construction contractors account for a larger proportion of total sales. These establishments are known as retail in the trade. This is a shortening of the 1987 SIC "Building Materials, Hardware, Garden Supply, And Mobile Home Dealers".</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>622</Code><Description>General merchandise stores</Description><Definition>The term "General merchandise stores" is used in both the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:This major group includes retail stores which sell a number of lines of merchandise, such as dry goods, apparel and accessories, furniture and home furnishings, small wares, hardware, and food. The stores included in this group are known by such names as department stores, variety stores, general merchandise stores, and general stores. Establishments primarily engaged in selling used general merchandise are classified in Industry Group 593, and those selling general merchandise by mail, vending machine, or direct selling are classified in Industry Group 596. NAICS definition:Industries in the General Merchandise Stores subsector retail new general merchandise from fixed point-of-sale locations. Establishments in this subsector are unique in that they have the equipment and staff capable of retailing a large variety of goods from a single location. This includes a variety of display equipment and staff trained to provide information on many lines of products.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>623</Code><Description>Food stores</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes retail stores primarily engaged in selling food for home preparation and consumption. Establishments primarily engaged in selling prepared foods and drinks for consumption on the premises are classified in Major Group 58, and stores primarily engaged in selling packaged beers and liquors are classified in Industry 5921.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>624</Code><Description>Automotive dealers and service stations</Description><Definition>This major SIC group includes retail dealers selling new and used automobiles, boats, recreational vehicles, utility trailers, and motorcycles including mopeds; those selling new automobile parts and accessories; and gasoline service stations. Automobile repair shops maintained by establishments engaged in the sale of new automobiles are also included. Establishments primarily engaged in the sale of used automobiles parts are classified in Wholesale Trade, Industry 5015.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>625</Code><Description>Apparel and accessory stores</Description><Definition>This major SIC group includes retail stores primarily engaged in selling new clothing, shoes, hats, underwear, and related articles for personal wear and adornment. Furriers and custom tailors carrying stocks of materials are included.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>626</Code><Description>Home furniture and furnishings stores</Description><Definition>This major SIC group includes retail stores selling goods used for furnishing the home, such as furniture, floor coverings, draperies, glass and chinaware, domestic stoves, refrigerators, and other household electrical and gas appliances. Establishments selling electrical and gas appliances are included in this group only if the major part of their sales consists of articles for home use. These stores may also repair household appliances, radios, televisions, and stereo equipment, but establishments primarily engaged in repair of these products are classified in Division I, Services. Dealers primarily engaged in selling antique and secondhand furniture are classified in Industry Group 593. Stores furnishing interior decorator service are classified according to the merchandise handled.This is a shortened name for the 1987 SIC Major Group 57: Home Furniture, Furnishings, And Equipment Stores.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>627</Code><Description>Eating and drinking places</Description><Definition>This SIC major group includes establishments selling prepared foods and drinks for consumption on the premises; and also lunch counters and refreshment stands selling prepared foods and drinks for immediate consumption. Restaurants, lunch counters, and drinking places operated as a subordinate service facility by other establishments are not included in this industry, unless they are operated as leased departments by outside operators.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>628</Code><Description>Miscellaneous retail</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes retail establishments, not elsewhere classified. These establishments fall into the following categories: drug stores, liquor stores, used merchandise stores, miscellaneous shopping goods stores, nonstore retailers, fuel dealers, and miscellaneous retail stores, not elsewhere classified.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>700</Code><Description>Finance, insurance, and real estate</Description><Definition>This SIC division includes establishments operating primarily in the fields of finance, insurance, and real estate. Finance includes depository institutions, non-depository credit institutions, holding (but not predominantly operating) companies, other investment companies, brokers and dealers in securities and commodity contracts, and security and commodity exchanges. Insurance covers carriers of all types of insurance, and insurance agents and brokers. Real estate includes owners, lessors, lessees, buyers, sellers, agents, and developers of real estate. Establishments primarily engaged in the construction of buildings for sale (operative builders) are classified in Construction, Industry 1531</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>710</Code><Description>Depository and nondepository institutions</Description><Definition>Depository institutions SIC group includes institutions that are engaged in deposit banking or closely related functions, including fiduciary activities.  Nondepository institutions SIC group includes establishments engaged in extending credit in the form of loans, but not engaged in deposit banking.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>730</Code><Description>Other finance, insurance, and real estate</Description><Definition>Other Finance, Insurance, and Real Estate combines the following Major SIC Groups: Major Group 62: Security And Commodity Brokers, Dealers, Exchanges, And Services; Major Group 63: Insurance Carriers; Major Group 64: Insurance Agents, Brokers, And Service; Major Group 65: Real Estate; and Major Group 67: Holding And Other Investment Offices. It specifically excludes the SIC Major Group 60: Depository Institutions and the Major SIC Group 61: Non-depository Credit Institutions, which make up the rest of the SIC Division H: Finance, Insurance, And Real Estate.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>731</Code><Description>Security and commodity brokers</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments engaged in the underwriting, purchase, sale, or brokerage of securities and other financial contracts on their own account or for the account of others; and exchanges, exchange clearinghouses, and other services allied with the exchange of securities and commodities.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>732</Code><Description>Insurance carriers</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes carriers of insurance of all types, including reinsurance. Agents and brokers dealing in insurance and organizations rendering services to insurance carriers or to policyholders are classified in Major Group 64.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>733</Code><Description>Insurance agents, brokers, and services</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes agents and brokers dealing in insurance, and also organizations offering services to insurance companies and to policyholders.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>734</Code><Description>Real estate</Description><Definition>The term "real estate" is used in the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:This major group includes real estate operators, and owners and lessors of real property, as well as buyers, sellers, developers, agents, and brokers. NAICS definition:Industries in the Real Estate subsector group establishments that are primarily engaged in renting or leasing real estate to others; managing real estate for others; selling, buying, or renting real estate for others; and providing other real estate related services, such as appraisal services.This subsector includes equity Real Estate Investment Trusts (REITs) that are primarily engaged in leasing buildings, dwellings, or other real estate property to others. Mortgage REITs are classified in Subsector 525, Funds, Trusts, and Other Financial Vehicles.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>735</Code><Description>Combined real estate, insurance, etc.</Description><Definition>This SIC (1972) major group includes establishments not classifiable on the basis of predominant nature of business, generally small in size, which are regularly engaged in any combination of real estate, insurance, loans, or the practice of law. However, if any one of these activities constitutes the principal business, the establishment should not be classified in this major group, but should be classified in the industry provided for that activity.Under the 1987 SIC, combined real estate, insurance, etc., was reclassified to four 2-digit industries: Nondepository credit institutions; insurance agents, brokers, and services; real estate; and legal services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>736</Code><Description>Holding and other investment offices</Description><Definition>This major SIC group includes investment trusts, investment companies, holding companies, and miscellaneous investment offices.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>800</Code><Description>Services</Description><Definition>This (SIC) division includes establishments primarily engaged in providing a wide variety of services for individuals, business and government establishments, and other organizations. Hotels and other lodging places; establishments providing personal, business, repair, and amusement services; health, legal, engineering, and other professional services; educational institutions; membership organizations, and other miscellaneous services, are included. Establishments which provide specialized services closely allied to activities covered in other divisions are classified in such divisions.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>805</Code><Description>Hotels and other lodging places</Description><Definition>This major SIC group includes commercial and noncommercial establishments engaged in furnishing lodging, or lodging and meals, and camping space and camping facilities.This is a shortened name for the 1987 SIC Major Group 70: Hotels, Rooming Houses, Camps, And Other Lodging Places.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>810</Code><Description>Personal services</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments primarily engaged in providing services generally to individuals, such as laundries, dry-cleaning plants, portrait photographic studios, and beauty and barber shops. Also included are establishments operating as industrial launderers and those primarily engaged in providing linen supply services to commercial and business establishments.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>815</Code><Description>Private households</Description><Definition>The term "Private households" is used in both the SIC system and in NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems. SIC definition:This major (SIC) group includes private households which employ workers who serve on or about the premises in occupations usually considered as domestic service. Households classified in this major group may employ individuals such as cooks, laundresses, maids, sitters, butlers, personal secretaries, and managers of personal affairs; and outside workers, such as gardeners, caretakers, and other maintenance workers. NAICS definitionIndustries in the Private Households NAICS subsector include private households that engage in employing workers on or about the premises in activities primarily concerned with the operation of the household. These private households may employ individuals, such as cooks, maids, and butlers, and outside workers, such as gardeners, caretakers, and other maintenance workers.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>820</Code><Description>Business services</Description><Definition>This SIC major group includes establishments primarily engaged in rendering services, not elsewhere classified, to business establishments on a contract or fee basis, such as advertising, credit reporting, collection of claims, mailing, reproduction, stenographic, news syndicates, computer programming, photocopying, duplicating, data processing, services to buildings, and help supply services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>825</Code><Description>Automotive repair, services, and parking</Description><Definition>This major SIC group includes establishments primarily engaged in furnishing automotive repair, rental, leasing, and parking services to the general public. Similar facilities owned and operated by concerns for their own use and not for the general public are treated as auxiliary establishments. Establishments primarily engaged in finance leasing of passenger cars and trucks are classified in Finance, Industry 6159. Automotive repair shops operated by establishments engaged in the sale of new automobiles are classified in Retail Trade, Industry 5511; and those operated by gasoline service stations are classified in Retail Trade, Industry 5541. Repair shops of railroad companies are classified in Railroad Transportation, Major Group 40; and establishments repairing ships and boats are classified in Manufacturing, Industry Group 373.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>830</Code><Description>Miscellaneous repair services</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments engaged in miscellaneous repair services. It does not include some repair services of which the most important are: repair to structures, which is classified in Construction, Division C; electronic computer and computer peripheral equipment repair, which is classified in Industry 7378; automotive repair, which is classified in Industry Group 753; clothing repair, which is classified in Industry 7219; and shoe repair, which is classified in Industry 7251.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>835</Code><Description>Amusement and recreation services</Description><Definition>This major SIC group includes establishments engaged in providing amusement or entertainment services, not elsewhere classified. Establishments primarily engaged in operating motion picture theaters are classified in Industry Group 783, and those operating museums, art galleries, arboreta, and botanical and zoological gardens are classified in Major Group 84.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>840</Code><Description>Motion pictures</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments producing and distributing motion pictures, exhibiting motion pictures in commercially operated theaters, and furnishing services to the motion picture industry. The term motion pictures, as used in this major group, includes similar productions for television or other media using film, tape, or other means.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>845</Code><Description>Health services</Description><Definition>This major SIC group includes establishments primarily engaged in furnishing medical, surgical, and other health services to persons. Establishments of associations or groups, such as Health Maintenance Organizations (HMOs), primarily engaged in providing medical or other health services to members are included, but those which limit their services to the provision of insurance against hospitalization or medical costs are classified in Insurance, Major Group 63. Hospices are also included in this major group and are classified according to the primary service provided.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>850</Code><Description>Legal services</Description><Definition>This industry appears in both SIC and NAICS tables. This major SIC group includes establishments which are headed by members of the bar and are engaged in offering legal advice or legal services. The NAICS subsector includes offices of lawyers, offices of notaries, title abstract and settlement offices, and other legal services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>855</Code><Description>Educational services</Description><Definition>The term "Educational services" is used in both the SIC and NAICS, but it does not have the same definition in both systems.SIC definition: This SIC major group (82) includes establishments providing academic or technical instruction. Also included are establishments providing educational services such as libraries, student exchange programs, and curriculum development. Schools for the instruction of beauticians and cosmetologists are classified in Industry 7231, and barber colleges are classified in Industry 7241. Establishments primarily engaged in providing job training for the unemployed, the underemployed, the handicapped, and to persons who have a job market disadvantage because of lack of education, job skill or experience are classified in Industry 8331.NAICS definition:The Educational Services (NAICS) sector comprises establishments that provide instruction and training in a wide variety of subjects. This instruction and training is provided by specialized establishments, such as schools, colleges, universities, and training centers. These establishments may be privately owned and operated for profit or not for profit, or they may be publicly owned and operated. They may also offer food and accommodation services to their students. For the public sector, the income and employment are classified by level of government- federal, state, and local. The estimates for the federal government are sub classified into civilian and military. The different treatment of the private and public sectors means that BEA's state and local government industry includes public education, public hospitals, and other types of government services while BEA reports only private schools in its educational services industry corresponding to NAICS code 61 and only private hospitals in its hospitals industry corresponding to NAICS code 622.  Educational services (NAICS) are usually delivered by teachers or instructors that explain, tell, demonstrate, supervise, and direct learning. Instruction is imparted in diverse settings, such as educational institutions, the workplace, or the home through correspondence, television, or other means. It can be adapted to the particular needs of the students, for example sign language can replace verbal language for teaching students with hearing impairments. All industries in the sector share this commonality of process, namely, labor inputs of instructors with the requisite subject matter expertise and teaching ability.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>860</Code><Description>Social services</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes establishments providing social services and rehabilitation services to those persons with social or personal problems requiring special services and to the handicapped and the disadvantaged. Also included are organizations soliciting funds to be used directly for these and related services.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>865</Code><Description>Museums, botanical, zoological gardens</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes museums, art galleries, arboreta, and botanical and zoological gardens. These establishments are often of historical, educational, or cultural interest.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>870</Code><Description>Membership organizations</Description><Definition>This major (SIC) group includes organizations operating on a membership basis for the promotion of the interests of their members. Included are organizations such as trade associations; professional membership organizations; labor unions and similar labor organizations; and political and religious organizations. This major group does not include business establishments operated by membership organizations, which are classified according to their primary activity.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>875</Code><Description>Engineering and management services</Description><Definition>The Engineering and Management Services major SIC group includes establishments primarily engaged in providing engineering, architectural, and surveying services; accounting, auditing, and bookkeeping services; research, development, and testing services; and management and public relations services.This is a shortened name for the 1987 SIC Major Group 87: Engineering, Accounting, Research, Management, And Related Services</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>880</Code><Description>Miscellaneous services</Description><Definition>This SIC industry major group includes establishments primarily providing services, not elsewhere classified, such as authors, lecturers, radio commentators, song writers, weather forecasters, writers, and artists working on their own account.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>900</Code><Description>Government and government enterprises</Description><Definition>Government includes the executive, legislative, judicial, administrative and regulatory activities of Federal, state, and local governments. It includes the military. Government enterprises are government agencies that cover a substantial portion of their operating costs by selling goods and services to the public and that maintain their own separate accounts.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>910</Code><Description>Federal civilian</Description><Definition>A sub-group of "government and government enterprises". Congressional staff and the U.S. Postal Service are included in this category.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>920</Code><Description>Military</Description><Definition>A sub-group of "Government and government enterprises, " this major group includes government establishments primarily engaged in national security and national affairs. The estimates of wages and salaries for the military services consist of cash wages (including allowances) of full-time personnel of the armed services (including the Coast Guard), cash wages of the members of the Reserves including the National Guard, and pay-in-kind received by the full-time and reserve enlisted personnel of the armed services.Military employment is measured as the number of military personnel assigned to active duty units that are stationed in the area plus the number of military reserve unit members. The estimates of active duty employment for the Army, Air Force, Navy, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard are based on the annual averages of 12 monthly observations, for a given year, from reports received from each branch of service. Navy personnel assigned to ships and other mobile units and Marines assigned to Fleet Marine Force units are measured according to the units' home ports rather than their actual locations as of the reporting date. The measure of the employment of the military Reserves--including the National Guard--is confined to members of reserve units that meet regularly for training. The state estimates are based on fiscal year--ending September 30--tabulations of military reserve strength provided by the Department of Defense.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>930</Code><Description>State and local</Description><Definition>"State and local" is a sub-group of Government and government enterprises.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>931</Code><Description>State government</Description><Definition>A sub-group of Government and Government Enterprises.Estimates of government wages and salaries, government earnings, government compensation, and government employment are presented in four pieces: Federal civilian; military; state government; and local government.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>932</Code><Description>Local government</Description><Definition>A sub-group of Government and Government Enterprises.Estimates of government wages and salaries, government earnings, government compensation, and government employment are presented in four pieces: Federal civilian; military; state government; and local government.</Definition></LINE></TABLE_DEFINITIONS>
