<TABLE_DEFINITIONS Table="SAINC50" Name="Personal current taxes" Source="USDOC/BEA/RD"><LINE><Code>10</Code><Description>Personal income (thousands of dollars)</Description><Definition>Consists of the income that persons receive in return for their provision of labor, land, and capital used in current production as well as other income, such as personal current transfer receipts. In the state and local personal income accounts the personal income of an area represents the income received by or on behalf of the persons residing in that area. It is calculated as the sum of wages and salaries, supplements to wages and salaries, proprietors' income with inventory valuation (IVA) and capital consumption adjustments (CCAdj), rental income of persons with capital consumption adjustment (CCAdj), personal dividend income, personal interest income, and personal current transfer receipts, less contributions for government social insurance plus the adjustment for residence.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>15</Code><Description>Less: Personal current taxes</Description><Definition>Tax payments (net of refunds) made by persons to government agencies other than government enterprises that are not chargeable to business expense. These payments primarily consist of taxes on income, including realized capital gains income, and on personal property, as well as several miscellaneous taxes, licenses, and fees. They do not include personal contributions for government social insurance.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>16</Code><Description>Equals: Disposable personal income</Description><Definition>The income available to persons for spending or saving. It is equal to personal income less personal current taxes.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>20</Code><Description>Population (persons)</Description><Definition>The number of individuals (both civilian and military) who reside in a given area.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>30</Code><Description>Per capita personal income (dollars)</Description><Definition>The personal income of a given area divided by the resident population of the area. See "personal income."</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>50</Code><Description>Per capita disposable personal income (dollars)</Description><Definition>Disposable personal income of a given area divided by the resident population of the area. See "disposable personal income."</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>60</Code><Description>Personal current taxes</Description><Definition>Tax payments (net of refunds) made by persons to government agencies other than government enterprises that are not chargeable to business expense. These payments primarily consist of taxes on income, including realized capital gains income, and on personal property, as well as several miscellaneous taxes, licenses, and fees. They do not include personal contributions for government social insurance.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>70</Code><Description>Federal government</Description><Definition>The term "Federal government" refers to personal current taxes to the federal government. This line total includes tax payments on income retained by fiduciaries on behalf of individuals.See Disposable Personal Income.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>80</Code><Description>Income taxes (net of refunds)</Description><Definition>Income taxes (net of refunds) consist of individual income tax payments to the Federal Government, net of refunds.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>81</Code><Description>Income taxes (gross)</Description><Definition>Income taxes (gross) represents the sum of the income taxes that are withheld, usually by employers, from wages and salaries; the quarterly payments of estimated taxes on income that is usually not subject to withholding; and final settlements, which is additional tax payments that are made when the tax returns for a year are filed or as a result of audits by the Federal Government.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>82</Code><Description>Less: Refunds</Description><Definition>Refunds refers to income tax returns, including refunds on realized net capital gains taxes , which are netted out of taxes paid when calculating personal current taxes.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>120</Code><Description>State governments</Description><Definition>The term "state governments" refers to personal current taxes to state governments.See Disposable Personal Income.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>130</Code><Description>Income taxes</Description><Definition>Income tax payments by individuals that exclude refunds.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>150</Code><Description>Motor vehicle licenses</Description><Definition>Payments for motor vehicle and operators' licenses are distributed by state based mainly on pertinent annual state data from Census Bureau's state Government Tax Collections (SGTC) supplemented by Federal Highway Administration data.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>160</Code><Description>Other taxes</Description><Definition>Other taxes consists largely of hunting and fishing taxes and other license taxes to state governments, and of miscellaneous fees (marriage licenses, registration of pleasure boats, and licenses for pets) to local governments. See Disposable Personal Income.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>180</Code><Description>Local governments</Description><Definition>The term "Local governments" refers to personal current taxes to local governments.See Disposable Personal Income.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>190</Code><Description>Income taxes</Description><Definition>Income tax payments by individuals that exclude refunds.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>200</Code><Description>Motor vehicle licenses</Description><Definition>Payments for motor vehicle and operators' licenses are distributed by state based mainly on pertinent annual state data from Census Bureau's state Government Tax Collections (SGTC) supplemented by Federal Highway Administration data.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>210</Code><Description>Other taxes</Description><Definition>Other taxes consists largely of hunting and fishing taxes and other license taxes to state governments, and of miscellaneous fees (marriage licenses, registration of pleasure boats, and licenses for pets) to local governments. See Disposable Personal Income.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>230</Code><Description>State and local personal property taxes</Description><Definition>These payments consist of the payments of taxes on the tangible and intangible personal property of individuals.See Disposable personal income.</Definition></LINE></TABLE_DEFINITIONS>
